<data>
  <title>
      Mesoamérica Resiste (Inside) from the Beehive Design Collective
  </title>
  <link>
    http://beehivecollective.org/beehive_poster/mesoamerica-resiste/
  </link>

  <stories>  



<story>
  <label>The view from the grassroots</label>
<region
  x="0.0"
  y="0.0"
  width="1.0"
  height="0.5"
/>
  <html>
    <p>Opening up the poster, the world on the inside is drawn from the perspective of an ant on the ground at the base of a towering ceiba tree. This ground’s eye view reflects the experiences of those who are rooted in a place and directly affected by the plans on the map. Between the roots of the ceiba, lively scenes illuminate stories of grassroots organizing and community resilience. This graphic documents many examples
  of alternatives to top-down development plans, highlighting resistance led by Indigenous peoples who have fought back against genocide and ongoing threats to their survival.</p>

    <p>The Ceiba tree’s spreading buttress roots hold the scenes together and tell an overarching story of rootedness. This tree serves as a gathering
    place, a beacon in the center of town that brings people together to share stories and announce calls to action.</p>

    <p>A multitude of characters symbolize strategies and tactics
    for building and defending autonomy. Every critter in the poster is based on a real species native to somewhere between Mexico and Colombia. 400 individual species of insects, plants, and animals give a glimpse of the incredible biodiversity of the region.</p>
  </html>
</story>

<story>
    <label>Two ghostly strands</label>
    <region
      x="0.07630"
      y="0.03473"
      width="0.13835"
      height="0.20346"
    />
    <html>
      Two ghostly strands spiral down around the trunk of the ceiba. The creatures here are all extinct, endangered, threatened, or vulnerable, but in spirit they’re alive and fighting fiercely. The strands are interwoven like the double helix of a DNA strand, to show the interconnectedness of the whole web of life.
    </html>
</story>

<story>
  <label>The upper layers of the canopy</label>
  <region
    x="0.61846"
    y="0.00831"
    width="0.16170"
    height="0.07860"
  />
  <html>
    The rainforest holds its richness in the upper layers of the canopy, which nurtures the life below. Once trees are cut down, the soil left behind is weak, and the ecological damage is irreparable. The loss of rainforests
    is mirrored by the loss of cultural heritage, which is also being rapidly fragmented and eroded.
  </html>
</story>

<story>
  <label>The spinal cord of Plan Mesoamerica</label>
    <region
  x="0.86065"
  y="0.01949"
  width="0.05468"
  height="0.08268"
/>
  <html>In the top right corner of
the poster, power lines march over the horizon. Under construction since 2007, the electric interconnection plan (SIEPAC) lays the groundwork for powering factories and industrial infrastructure. Power lines that would ultimately stretch from
Colombia to North America particularly threaten the communities and ecosystems of the Darien Gap, a large stretch
of wetlands and forests along the border between Panama and Colombia where there are no roads (the only gap in the Panamerican Highway). While energy is generated to meet the demands of big business, some rural communities lack access to electricity for basic needs or face exorbitant rates. A mob of birds flies at the tower, knocking it down and re-wiring for energy on a local scale.
  </html>
</story>

<story>
  <label>Hydroelectric Dams</label>
  <region
  x="0.77955"
  y="0.13803"
  width="0.05962"
  height="0.05276"
/>
  <html>One foot of the power tower sucks its energy from a hydroelectric dam, flooding out entire villages and putting vast areas
of habitat underwater. The dam, dubbed Clean Development,
is backed with military might
and produces electricity to power far removed factories and transport routes.
  </html>
</story>

<story>
  <label>A wave of letters</label>
<region
  x="0.75518"
  y="0.14093"
  width="0.05911"
  height="0.04252"
/>
  <html>A wave of letters from the public flies at the dam, as people take up their pens in defense of their community. The high
volume of public opinion fractures the dam and opens up time and space for a variety of resistance tactics to be used.
  </html>
</story>

<story>
  <label>Social Spiders</label>
  <region
  x="0.69306"
  y="0.13445"
  width="0.07177"
  height="0.03800"
/>
  <html>In the shadow of the power
lines, social spiders stitch together an urban squat as they
collaboratively rebuild their
community. Economic forces
have pushed them to the margins of
the city, yet they continue working together. Social spiders are not territorial or aggressive like many solitary species, but instead cooperate to build massive nests to care for their entire community. In the face of large scale development projects that threaten to uproot their new homes, the spiders are a reminder of urban struggles for land rights and recognition.
  </html>
</story>

<story>
  <label>The Land Grab</label>
  <region
  x="0.84714"
  y="0.17290"
  width="0.09167"
  height="0.11133"
/>
  <html>A monolithic copy machine dominates the righthand side of the poster as it
spews out one-size-fits-all development plans. This machine rips
up land, forcing it through
a paper tray into where gas pumps write with oil-barrel toner. The pre-written plans speed on to the second level
where
whirlygig
businessmen shake
hands, rubber stamp permits, and exchange stacks of cash. The top of the copier spits out blueprints for large-scale infrastructure development projects.
</html>
</story>

  <story>
    <label>Bulldozer</label>
    <region
      x="0.86040"
      y="0.30390"
      width="0.08184"
      height="0.04755"
      />
    <html>The road-paving bulldozer cuts
  through rural and urban areas
  alike in order to provide easy
  and quick getaway routes for
  trucks hauling their goods across
  borders. Over 80% of Project Mesoamerica’s funding is going towards
  transportation infrastructure, but these are highways being built for big industry, not for communities. Superhighways that claim to “connect Mesoamerica” are actually making large areas of land impassable for pedestrians and migratory animals, displacing homes and productive farmland, and charging high tolls that limit public use.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Airport</label>
    <region
      x="0.77072"
      y="0.16178"
      width="0.12450"
      height="0.06851"
      />
    <html>A cornfield faces off against an airplane
trying to land at a new airport outside of Mexico City, one of the first projects proposed as part of
Plan Puebla Panama.
People in the town of San Salvador Atenco organized and successfully fought back to keep their land from being expropriated for the
airport. This image of campesinos in Atenco, wielding machetes to defend their land, quickly became
emblematic of popular protest against the PPP.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Three fronts of resistance working together</label>
    <region
      x="0.83840"
      y="0.23730"
      width="0.12162"
      height="0.12800"
      />
    <html>
      <p>Farmers, teachers, and workers are joining forces to tackle the tentacles of the land grabbing copy machine. These important social sectors are represented by three of the most important crops in the region, culturally and nutritionally: the three sisters of corns, beans, and squash.</p>
      <p>Planted together in milpas, a traditional system of farming in Mesoamérica, these plants support each other, each improving the growth of the others.</p>
    </html>   
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Tequio</label>
    <region
  x="0.76256"
  y="0.29317"
  width="0.08599"
  height="0.03666"
/>
    <html>
    Little beansprouts are learning
about the value of Tequio, or collective work, from their teachers who are on strike and still educating their students through the struggle. The concept
of a community coming together and all pitching in to get work done is found in many cultures and languages throughout the world.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>The People's Media</label>
    <region
      x="0.76546"
      y="0.20931"
      width="0.09403"
      height="0.09309"
    />
    <html>
<p>The pedal-powered media machine rides into the scene, using media by
and for the people. They cut through the stream of development plans
from the copier with their screen-printed posters, as
they record stories from the frontlines and broadcast
them through alternative, independent media. The bees are taking the power of the
media into their own hands to build resistance movements, from small-scale distribution of pamphlets to bold takeovers of mass media, like in Oaxaca in 2006.</p>
<p>The free media machine catapults seed bombs at the land grab. The seed balls are a mix of seeds, soil, and clay that serve to reclaim damaged land for cultivation.</p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Tourism</label>
    <region
      x="0.80157"
      y="0.36829"
      width="0.13356"
      height="0.09301"
    />
    <html>In the bottom right corner of the poster, a cruise ship invades the coast. The ship is based off an amphibious landing
￼￼craft used by the U.S. marines to deploy troops on the shores of Central America. The chompy teeth are tourists going on holiday to unwind as they gobble up a packaged experience.
They don’t see beyond billboards that offer up Indigenous culture for sale and entertainment, and local people for serving food and cleaning toilets. Relying on racism, the tourist industry exploits local communities of color while selling the idea that a privileged
few are entitled to their vacationland.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Behind the billboard facade</label>
    <region
      x="0.76001"
      y="0.30921"
      width="0.12989"
      height="0.10031"
    />
    <html>
      <p>A two-sided billboard works to homogenize all cultures and keep peoples thoughts only skin deep, as it sells tanning lotion to white tourists and skin whitening cream to local people of color.</p>
      <p>Behind the billboard
facade, a real-life manatee, crab, and turtle are representatives of coastal communities fighting for recognition of ancestral lands. Defending their cultural
identity, the Indigenous Garifuna communities on the Atlantic Coast
are confronting paramilitary violence, which is used to enforce Illegal land sales. Their drums break through the colonial lie of ‘discovering empty beaches.’</p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Market</label>
    <region
      x="0.53735"
      y="0.33415"
      width="0.16410"
      height="0.11754"
    />
    <html>
Shopping carts pushed by
genetically modified palm, corn,
and soy creatures are rushing in
on newly-paved highways, attempting to invade a traditional local market with an arsenal of junk food and
copyrighted genetic bombs. The
market resists the invasion with
the strength of its cultural and ecological diversity, forming a blockade of DNA strands to keep out these mono-cropped monsters of industrial agriculture.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Meanwhile, an 18-wheeler truck…</label>
    <region
  x="0.68186"
  y="0.37163"
  width="0.12378"
  height="0.11725"
/>
    <html>
      Meanwhile, an 18-wheeler truck, hauling in mass produced, highly subsidized, and nutritionally void “food products”
confronts another blockade on the right side of the market. This blockade is formed by youth who are also sending these big brands a message: take back your trash!
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Inside the market</label>
    <region
      x="0.52447"
      y="0.29585"
      width="0.19906"
      height="0.07632"
    />
    <html>
      <p>Inside the market, local economies and native food systems thrive. All the vendors are pollinators, the creatures that flowering plants need to produce fruit. Providing habitat for pollinators is an essential part of healthy, biodiverse farming.</p>
      <p>The yucca moth, for example, is the sole pollinator of yucca; without this moth, the yucca plant can’t go to seed.
      All the shoppers in the market are seed dispersers, and the market itself represents a living seed bank.</p>
      <p>Everywhere there is food in this scene, seeds are included: vendors are packaging, exchanging, collecting, and sprouting seeds, nurturing hundreds of local varieties of plants and protecting their food sovereignty for generations to come.</p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Women on the front lines</label>
    <region
      x="0.27840"
      y="0.33707"
      width="0.18801"
      height="0.14952"
    />
    <html>
      <p>A scheming puppet master stands at a podium, controlling the many forms of military force that carry out the list of conquests. The use of force against people has taken many forms throughout the Americas, including death squads, private security forces, militarized riot police, organized crime, and plain-clothed paramilitary.</p>
      <p>The invaders are unable to advance as they find themselves surrounded by a blockade of women
  defending their land, safety, and community. Each character carries a marking of a female and is using
  her natural defenses, like the porcupine who has shot her
  quills into the face of the paramilitary.
  Women and children put themselves on the front lines during countless standoffs between armed forces and unarmed civilians in defense of their communities.
      </p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <region
      x="0.46456"
      y="0.33329"
      width="0.05218"
      height="0.07652"
    />
    <label>Ancestors, ¡Presente!</label>
    <html>
    An ancient glyptodont roars and swings her armored tail, representing the spirits of ancestors that are being disturbed by the mine. Skeletons of extinct animals appear in a few other scenes, their presence reminding us of all who have come before us in the struggles for justice.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Open pit mine</label>
    <region
      x="0.45455"
      y="0.40978"
      width="0.09922"
      height="0.07260"
    />
    <html>
    Giant mining machines dig into the earth, employing dangerous and exploitative labor practices while disregarding the environment and health of nearby communities. Cerrejón, the worlds largest open pit coal mine,
    forcibly removed Wayuu and Afro-Colombian communities from their land. Cyanide leaching from Goldcorp’s Marlin mine in Guatemala has severely contaminated the groundwater. Both have served as warnings and case studies for the organized resistance to mining across the Americas.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Water for Profit</label>
    <region
      x="0.01626"
      y="0.28792"
      width="0.10789"
      height="0.12271"
    />
    <html>
      <p>The monster of water privatization looms over the stream, seizing water
      from the commons and locking it away with dollar
      values. Giant drinking straws feed into a tower of industries that rob communities of their drinking water through over-use and pollution.
      Stacked from top to bottom are: bottled water, mining,
      textiles, cattle ranching, and golf courses. The water trucks on chain
      leashes are fierce attack dogs protecting the interests of the water monster; one truck sells
      drinking water, while the the other blasts water mixed with tear gas to disperse protests.
      </p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>A trio of water creatures</label>
    <region
      x="0.13045"
      y="0.26300"
      width="0.07792"
      height="0.07508"
    />
    <html>
      Taking a stance on the nearby tree root, a trio of water creatures are caught in a tug-of-war. Pulling with all their might, they work
to take back the water for its use as a life giving force.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Water for life</label>
    <region
      x="0.09512"
      y="0.25228"
      width="0.09274"
      height="0.07539"
    />
    <html>
    Moss covered toad statues illustrate the age-old uses of water - drinking,
    cooking, bathing, and washing. At the top of the stream an Uo toad signifies the rainy season
    and fertility brought by water. A reminder that water is life, the toads’ everyday use of water for basic needs is a form of resistance to selling off water to private interests.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Reclaiming water from pollution</label>
    <region
      x="0.09991"
      y="0.35523"
      width="0.05279"
      height="0.02830"
    />
    <html>Underfoot of the menacing water monster, a team of bacteria
form a bucket-brigade to collect the polluted water and reclaim
it through a “living machine”
filtration system. Polls of living
organisms from reeds, lilies, and
water hyacinth to snails and clams work together in a multistage process of water purification.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Pirate Radio</label>
    <region
      x="0.02035"
      y="0.39752"
      width="0.08808"
      height="0.05827"
    />
    <html>
      The independent radio station or radio libre (free radio) beams out news and culturally valuable music over the airways. In situations where mass media is tightly controlled by oppressive governments, community radio may be the only way for transmitting critical information about social movements. Using a small-scale water wheel, the station powers itself as an example of autonomous energy production.
    </html>
  </story>


  <story>
    <label>Golden toads</label>
    <region
      x="0.12653"
      y="0.41729"
      width="0.05948"
      height="0.04260"
    />
    <html>
    <p>
    Frogs and toads are highly sensitive to changes in an ecosystem and serve as warning signs of environmental catastrophe. The demise of the golden toad marked the first time
that the scientific establishment officially attributed an extinction to climate change, but they are not the only victims. Against all odds, a ring of eggs floats in the water around the mating toads, reminiscent of cycles of the moon.
    </p>
  </html>
  </story>


  <story>
    <label>Birth</label>
    <region
      x="0.15965"
      y="0.33729"
      width="0.08405"
      height="0.05527"
    />
    <html>
Deep inside a womb-like cave formed by the tree roots, a scene of fertility portrays a
vampire bat midwife assisting a birth. She is surrounded by herbal medicines used for traditional and Indigenous healing practices. The plants hanging in the cave are all related to fertility and women’s reproductive health. Midwifery and other non-Western medical practices have resiliently survived despite the bio-medical industry’s attempts to discredit and destroy them.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Coastal Monoculture</label>
    <region
      x="0.02489"
      y="0.24446"
      width="0.10016"
      height="0.06625"
    />
    <html>A bulldozer
crashes through the roots of a mangrove ecosystem, dragging in fencing and
an industrial shrimp farm in its wake. Mangroves protect the coast from erosion with their massive root systems, creating a unique ecosystem, nursey, and sanctuary for young aquatic creatures. Industrial shrimp farming is a rapidly growing industry that threatens mangroves worldwide. This polluting monoculture displaces the marine life which provides essential protein sources for local communities.
    </html>
  </story>
  

  <story>
    <label>Refugees</label>
    <region
      x="0.02292"
      y="0.15081"
      width="0.08734"
      height="0.09897"
    />
    <html>Crying out in alarm, a flock of birds bursts into the air above the disturbed mangrove forest. The birds clutch their nests and young, forced to flee as their habitat is destroyed by infrastructure projects. The birds also tell a story of people who fled the scorched earth policies, genocide, and civil wars in Guatemala, El Salvador, and Nicaragua from the 1960s-1980s. The broken nests show the destruction and separation of families in exile.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Returning</label>
    <region
      x="0.19249"
      y="0.02681"
      width="0.12662"
      height="0.07251"
    />
    <html>
      <p>Emerging
    from the forest canopy, the
    birds return home after
    the war. Some of them had organized in exile and fought to
    return home as recognized organizations.</p>
    <p>Youth are recording historic memory by interviewing their elders and broadcasting to the whole community.</p>
    <p>They carry examples of organizing and solidarity: a childcare cooperative, saving seeds and planting hope for the future, weaving as a metaphor for the social fabric of
    community, mobilizing and educating through
    petitions and independent media. At the front of the line two young birds remind us that
    youth are leaders in the movement, carrying photos of the
    disappeared.</p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Fiesta</label>
    <region
      x="0.23704"
      y="0.20427"
      width="0.16202"
      height="0.15823"
    />
    <html>
      Spirits and the living mingle together in this lively
fiesta, as they sing and dance in honor of
the four elements surrounding the scene; earth, air, water,
and fire. Gathered around the fire, elders and ancestors pass down wisdom to a
younger generation — sharing stories of resistance, knowing that wins, losses, and the
journey between are all
reasons to come together. When existence is resistance, the seemingly simple act of gathering carries great significance.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Historical memory</label>
      <region
        x="0.17276"
        y="0.35920"
        width="0.14787"
        height="0.10588"
      />
    <html>
      <p>In the roots below the bat cave and the
      fiesta, caterpillar youth are painting a mural
      of a monarch butterfly in a field of corn,
      the pattern on its wings morphing into
      strong fists of struggle. The butterfly has
      been widely used in today’s migrant rights movements as a symbol of freedom and courage to cross borders.</p>
      <p>The caterpillars in this scene were inspired by meeting with HIJOS in Guatemala, a group formed a few years after the peace accords in 1996. They are the children of those who were disappeared during the civil war, still fighting for justice. Murals
      educate about the past and keep collective memory alive, using art as to transform a
      violent history into something filled with beauty
      and power. The youth are
      surrounded by references
      to memory and oral history.
      Flowers, plants, a conch shell, music, and traditional weavings are all passing knowledge and stories down through generations, their voices spiraling out in the form of volutas. The voluta is like a speech bubble. It is adapted from a Mayan glyph representing speaking and listening. Throughout the poster it symbolizes the power of the word.</p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>    
    <label>The community assembly</label>
    <region
      x="0.37738"
      y="0.19010"
      width="0.21635"
      height="0.13749"
    />
    <html>
      Representatives of communities affected by Project Mesoamérica gather in a circle at the center of the poster to discuss their common struggles and plans for collective action. Some of the
      characters bring items from their communities, signaling that they’ve traveled far to be here, and that organizing efforts have been coordinated
      across the region. Unlike the top-down decision making that governs the “official” plans for the region, many voices are valued in
      his process of participatory, horizontal communication. The stories transmitted at this gathering join together in a spiral that
      symbolizes the conversation taking
      place. Documenting and spreading the word is also essential; recording equipment appears around the circle to foster communication between generations and across cultures.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>The Ant Swarm</label>
    <region
      x="0.19466"
      y="0.10856"
      width="0.23569"
      height="0.11446"
    />
    <html>
      <p>A giant swarm of ants comes down the trunk of the Ceiba tree. The ants, like so many other little critters, play an essential role in the ecosystem. Scurrying beneath the dirt, they aerate the soil, making it possible for plants to grow, essentially laying the foundations for life on earth. While these ants seem small in the face of the entire forest, they outweigh all other animals and plants combined. The ants remind us that great changes are in the hands of the small and many. Working tirelessly, these miniscule creatures embody the phrase,
      la revolución es el trabajo de las hormigas (the revolution
      is ant’s work). Little by little, their collective work has the strength to achieve great transformations, which reminds us that together, we can create tremendous changes in the world around us.</p>

      <p>
        Some of the ants proudly
        carry messages from Indigenous communities in southern Mexico who have been slowly and steadily building autonomy for several decades. These sayings are Zapatista principles and also come from their experience of building “good government” councils, which encourage frequent rotation of leadership: “lead by obeying” the people in your community, they advise; “work from below, without seeking to rise to power;” “walk by asking questions.” Each ant is a different species, reminding us that the beauty of the world lies in its diversity - of cultures, of languages, of ways
        of being: “we are the same because we are different;” “a world where many worlds fit.” In the face of so
        many threats to the diversity of life on this planet, the ants converge at the base of the Ceiba to declare “Ya basta! Enough!”
      </p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Stories of Bees and Economies</label>
    <region
      x="0.56119"
      y="0.14136"
      width="0.17070"
      height="0.08270"
    />
    <html>
      <p>As European colonists invaded Central America, they brought with them the invasive European honey bee, which aggressively began to push the native Mesoamerican stingless bees out of their ecological niche. Today, deforestation, pollution, and industrial farming are destroying habitat and causing the collapse of pollinator species all over Central America. Bees are an indicator species, and the drastic decline of their populations may forecast a larger ecosystem collapse. Restoring native bee populations is vitally important to the health of ecosystems and agriculture globally, and is directly linked to the survival of Indigenous peoples and beekeeping knowledge. Traditional beekeeping is an intimate relationship between bees, people, culture,
      and the land.</p>
      <h4>Vanilla and stingless bees</h4>
      <p>Pollinators and the plants they
      pollinate need each other. The
      native Melipona bee and the vanilla plant share one of these specific symbiotic relationships. Melipona bees from southern Mexico are the only natural pollinators of the delicate vanilla orchid. Without this specialized interaction, vanilla orchids would only survive by hand pollination, making vanilla one of the most labor intensive crops in the world.</p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>An Alternative Economy: Design</label>
    <region
      x="0.68421"
      y="0.16764"
      width="0.05383"
      height="0.04177"
    />
    <html>
      Each terrace of the hive is buzzing as bees work on designing an economy to provide for their needs. As opposed to the accumulation of wealth that is central to the capitalist economy, this economy is centered around health, food, shelter and wellbeing. The Bees plan their economic system by studying the health and structure of their hive, taking notes, and mapping out routes for gathering local resources.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>An Alternative Economy: Production</label>
    <region
      x="0.72960"
      y="0.18216"
      width="0.04502"
      height="0.06450"
    />
    <html>
      Carpenter bees and other species of solitary bees
show solidarity by building
habitats for other pollinators. A worker-owned print shop produces paper from recycled materials.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>An Alternative Economy: Exchange</label>
    <region
      x="0.69933"
      y="0.26093"
      width="0.06413"
      height="0.05339"
    />
    <html>In contrast to the exploitative maps made by the colonizers, bumble bees, mason bees, and carder bees are mapping out a solidarity economy that is mutually beneficial. A bee on a conch shell phone busily takes orders while others prepare to send out bundles of heirloom seeds, honey, tortillas, candles, bee houses, and books, as part of a regional network that relies on local skills and goods.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>An Alternative Economy: Eating together</label>
    <region
      x="0.62940"
      y="0.23196"
      width="0.08249"
      height="0.05616"
    />
    <html>
      These bees have invited friends over for a meal and for a popular education workshop about direct trade. They explain how to connect with local farmers to get food straight
      from the farm to the table, cutting out the middleman. They use local bark to make DIY    biogas that heats the comal for cooking tortillas;
      next to it the same bark is
      mixed with honey to make
      balché, a traditional fermented mead.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>An Alternative Economy: Dividing the hive</label>
    <region
      x="0.68104"
      y="0.19608"
      width="0.05497"
      height="0.03479"
    />
    <html>
      Bees work on dividing the hive, a skill passed down through the generations by oral tradition. The stingless bees are kept in a specially-made box, as the bee logs (stacked on the left side of this scene) are in short supply due to deforestation. Survival of Melipona bees depends on knowledge from elder beekeepers. In conservation efforts, some scientists with “zoo” mentalities have destroyed hives they tried to protect by collecting them for study in labs. The stingless bees remind
      us of the vital connection between culture and ecology.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>An Alternative Economy: Reinvestment</label>
    <region
      x="0.65457"
      y="0.14533"
      width="0.03477"
      height="0.06208"
    />
    <html>
      <p>Unlike the one-way flows of the global economy, resources in the hive are recycled and reinvested.</p>
      <h4>Seed saving</h4>
      <p>Harvesting seeds and saving them to grow a new set of crops next season, the bees build sustainable sovereign food systems that will continue to feed their peoples
      for generations. Saving seed is an example of self-sufficiency and independence from industrial agriculture.
      </p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>An Alternative Economy: Composting</label>
    <region
      x="0.58990"
      y="0.22322"
      width="0.04451"
      height="0.03546"
    />
    <html>
      Turning food
      scraps and garden
      waste into lush
      fertile soil, the
      bees and worms
      build future food
      systems, literally starting from the ground up.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>An Alternative Economy: Most valued assets</label>
    <region
      x="0.53870"
      y="0.13475"
      width="0.07708"
      height="0.04777"
    />
    <html>
      <p>Safeguarded at the top of the hive, the bee larvae are highly valued as they provide the base of the next generation and an investment
      in the future. Seeds and eggs are the currency
      of the economy that runs this bee
      society; they are the
      concentrated units that all life comes from, and speak to the symbiotic relationship between plants and pollinators.</p>
      <h4>Seeds of the future</h4>
      <p>As the larvae grow, so does their education. The newbees
      learn to cooperate and play together while pumping out honey with a seesaw. Other youth share what they’ve learned about the colonial invasion of European stinging bees, through a mural and
      a play. Kites soar above, celebrating the young bees’ irrepressible spirit of resistance.</p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>An Alternative Economy: Astronomers</label>
    <region
      x="0.56220"
      y="0.11067"
      width="0.03839"
      height="0.02988"
    />
    <html>
      At the top of the hive, Melipona bees study the cosmos, learning from the cycles of the earth and moon. Informed by these natural cycles, the community can plan for planting and cultivating.
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Globalization from below</label>
    <region
      x="0.28675"
      y="0.18450"
      width="0.54325"
      height="0.13483"
    />
    <html>
      <p>Facing the serious dangers of colony collapse, over 50 bee species have come together to build an alternative economic system that emphasizes horizontal and equitable relationships, while providing the basic needs of their community.</p>
      <p>The values of an extractive economy have led us to a mass extinction crisis and climate chaos. The holistic values of a solidarity economy are part of the antidote to this crisis. Like the bees, rebuilding local and regional networks can help us deal with the challenges and consequences of a rapidly changing planet. All the critters defending their land between the roots of the Ceiba are showing us the meaning of globalization from below: reaching out across borders, cultures, and generations to link movements and support each other’s struggles for survival.
      </p>
    </html>
  </story>



  </stories>
</data>