<?xml version="1.0"?>
<data>
  <title>
      Flood The System
  </title>
  <link>
    http://Floodthesystem.net
  </link>

  <stories>  

    <story>
      <label>Flood the System: A VISION for movement momentum</label>
      <region
        x="0.00"
        y="0.00"
        width="1.0"
        height="0.46"
      />
      <html>
        <p><strong>We are in a time of incredible movement momentum.</strong> Hundreds of thousands of people are in motion in the streets around the world, demanding better wages, an end to police brutality, an end to economic austerity, and real systemic solutions to an increasingly chaotic global climate. We know that our movements are linked, and that the climate crisis is a symptom of capitalism, white supremacy, colonialism and patriarchy. In the lead up to United Nations climate negotiations in Paris this December, Flood the System is a call to action targeting the institutions that threaten our collective survival. As economic and political elites negotiate the future of capitalism, we will escalate tactically, create new organizing ecosystems and structures, and build the relationships necessary for a movement that can transform society. 
        </p>
        <p>
          <strong>This graphic was made by the arts &amp; cultural strategies working group of Flood the System to help us visualize the organizing arc of the next year.</strong> Water is the source of life, a sacred and increasingly scarce and endangered commons upon which we all depend. Water is also an amazing and inspiring metaphor for putting people power in motion. Water is found everywhere in the world, in formations as diverse as glaciers, geysers, tidepools, and tornadoes. Whether liquid, solid, or vapor, water is always moving, just like our resistance movements. Water navigates barriers creatively; like bodies in the streets, it can be calm and placid, raging and fierce, and everywhere in between. Water is resilient and relentless; it is the most powerful erosive force on the planet. It coaxes the smallest seeds grow.
        </p>
        <p>
          <strong>We’re calling on the power of water to help us share the story of Flood the System.</strong> We’re calling on water to inspire our organizing, our actions in the street, and our posture toward the long-haul work ahead. We’re calling on water to describe the escalation we’re picturing over the next year. This graphic helps us visualize working our way up to the Flood we envision, following our power down from the clouds in the sky and up from the aquifers below, seeing it flow across the landscape of organizing as it builds power and momentum, and showing it grow to rapids and eventually massive Flooding actions that have enough power to take down, bypass, and transform political and economic barriers to justice.
        </p>
      </html>
    </story>



    <story>
      <label>Why a Flood?</label>
      <region
  x="0.00027"
  y="0.13166"
  width="0.33333"
  height="0.32066"
/>
      <html>
        <p>On the left side of the graphic, we see the the sky starting to precipitate and formations of groundwater pooling below. The clouds, representing collective movement histories, are underscored by a swirling pressure system symbolizing multiple, interlocking systems of power and violence, including capitalism, patriarchy, white supremacy, colonialism.</p>

        <p>Descending to earth, lightning storms illuminate the landscape of social power like flashpoints of crisis: moments when power structures become widely visible and actionable to large segments of society. Rain represents the distilled conditions of our moment: the opportunities for change, and the moment-to-moment dynamics that move us to action. Rain mixes with soil in the muddy waters, the places where our ideas about change making start to get traction in the real world and play with others, becoming both messy and fertile. The aquifer underlies it all, a massive store of people power we must tap into achieve systemic change.</p>

        <p>This entire scene describes the necessity of learning from our history, taking leadership from frontline community experiences and people of color, analyzing power in our society, and taking bold, direct collective action.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

  <story>
    <label>Clouds: Collective Movement Histories</label>
    <region
      x="0.06322"
      y="0.18150"
      width="0.16061"
      height="0.08418"
    />
    <html>
      <p>The clouds are like the moisture still in the atmosphere after past floods. The US has a legacy of resistance history to be proud of and inspired by. Sometimes, resistance to injustice becomes so widespread and aligned that masses of people move together towards the same vision, effecting lasting changes in their wake. The abolition, civil rights, farmworker justice, Immigrant rights, global justice, first and second wave feminist, environmental, labor, prison abolition, anti-war, and Queer Liberation movements are some of these.</p>

      <p>Those who’ve come before us have left us lessons and showed us where there is still work to do. Particularly in the environmental movement, there is a need to learn and be humbled by this history. Living on stolen land transformed into an extractive, industrial landscape by stolen labor power, there can be no environmentalism without a commitment to anti-racism, anti-capitalism, anti-colonialism, and feminism. The land and the people tell the same story, and they both cry out for justice.</p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Pressure Systems: Intersecting Systems of Oppression</label>
    <region
      x="0.00201"
      y="0.13700"
      width="0.22032"
      height="0.08154"
    />
    <html>
      <p>We organize our movements and live our lives in a context of oppression. White supremacy, patriarchy, capitalism and colonialism are the root causes of the climate crisis. In order to make lasting, transformative change, we must align our work with other movements fighting the same systems.</p>

      <p>Here, we see a pressure system swirling into an energy center with enormous destructive potential. Such systems make up the atmosphere in which we organize. We breathe them in constantly and so they are also inside all of us, internalized and reproduced in our relationships with ourselves and others. They influence each other and intersect, working together to create a social reality of oppression, power, and exclusion that is complex and systemic. These systems are often the source of our rage, our commitment to work for justice, and our ferocity.</p>

      <p>We know that racism, sexism and the police are ready and willing to demobilize us as we work together to dismantle these systems. But when we work together across lines of traditional divide, we build power. And we only get better with practice. Flood the System has adopted a set of guiding principles to support us in this effort. (TODO: link to guiding principles &amp; anti racism doc)</p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Storms: Flash Points of Crisis</label>
    <region
      x="0.03280"
      y="0.23327"
      width="0.21354"
      height="0.11242"
    />
    <html>
      <p>Sometimes there is a flash point that illuminates systems of oppression, like the lightning storm shown here. When lightning flashes, a broad public can see these systems more clearly. Often this looks like a crisis, and often a crisis is a moment when big changes are possible because the status quo of power-holders is delegitimized. Dominant narratives about power are proven false in big, public ways, and in that moment of rupture, new stories about power can enter the public consciousness.</p>

      <p>Take, for example, the murder of Mike Brown and the non-indictment of Officer Darren Wilson. Consider climate catastrophies like Hurricanes Katrina and Sandy, or the stock market crash and foreclosure crisis of 2008. Each of these lightning bolts illuminated the ongoing violence and corruption of state and corporate interests because people rose up in clear, sustained protest, making the underlying long term crises of racism, climate chaos, and capitalism widely visible across the nation.</p>

      <p>These focusing moments fuel our social movements, opening up spaces where big changes can happen quickly. But it’s not enough to wait for and try to respond to these bolts of lightning. First of all, we never know where or when one will strike. Consider: how many young black men have been killed at the hands of police in the last decade? And yet 2014 was an unprecedented year of people organizing, shutting down highways and declaring at top volume: Black Lives Matter!</p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Rain: The Conditions for Change</label>
    <region
      x="0.12669"
      y="0.24811"
      width="0.10892"
      height="0.09752"
    />
    <html>
      <p>Droplets of rain -- the beginning of the Flood -- bring our attention out of the backdrop of history and power and down to earth, representing our recognition of our political moment.</p>

      <p>When we look around the organizing landscape today, we see massive numbers of courageous people in the streets fighting for Black lives, Indigenous sovereignty, #Not1More deportation, freedom from fear, and jobs with dignity.</p>

      <p>We also see the climate movement escalating. We recognize that climate is not “the issue” into which everyone else’s movements must fit, but a symptom of the same disease as police brutality, exploitive labor practices, poverty, and mass incarceration. </p>

      <p>Looking at all these conditions led <a href="https://risingtidenorthamerica.org/">Rising Tide</a> to put forward Flood the System, an organizing framework that points to climate change as a symptom of systems of oppression, offers a model for action that different kinds of groups can see themselves in, and ensures grassroots voices provide the leadership for the movement. </p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Muddy Waters: Fertile Soil</label>
    <region
      x="0.04940"
      y="0.34700"
      width="0.22813"
      height="0.04871"
    />
    <html>
      <p>When we begin to give our political visions traction in the real world, the results are rarely tidy.</p>

      <p>There are real tensions and competing commitments at play in our movement and struggle: we need to work locally AND globally, quickly AND accountably, democratically AND with frontline voices at the center. We have to build the world we need AND cope in the world we have.</p>

      <p>We’re often more practiced at critique, analysis, and even despair than we are at working with hope. And yet, we only get better at working together across difference by actually trying to work together across difference.</p>

      <p>Here, the rain drops can be seen churning up soil into muddy waters, our symbol for the fertile places where we grapple with and strategize about the complexities of our political moment, committed to struggling together for the long haul. Let’s churn the waters until they are dense with fertile silt and soil, and let’s keep asking ourselves and each other the hard questions that will make our movement truthful. And let’s make sure that we don’t get stuck in the mud, but use its vital energy to move ourselves and our work forward.</p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>Aquifier: Drawing Up Our Power from Below</label>
    <region
      x="0.01530"
      y="0.39124"
      width="0.31459"
      height="0.06982"
    />
    <html>
      <p>Our power comes from below. It resides in people in self organized groups and organizations that are already fighting for justice.  We can show our power through our willingness to withdraw our consent from unjust systems, which we do through taking direct action and practicing skills for a just transition.</p>

      <p>When we resist the current system of power by engaging in direct action, we recognize the power within us. Once we recognize our power, we see that a new world is possible and we can shift the power back to where it truly resides – with the people. The questions are: how do we withdraw our consent visibly, how long can we sustain it, and by what means?</p>

      <p>Flood the System is asking you to organize with others in your community on the frontlines of struggle to escalate in September, October, and November. Get louder, get bolder, get direct!  The climate and our communities need direct resistance to the attacks they face.  Will your community be a part of the flood? Will you engage in broad based, decentralized, strategic and targeted direct action in the lead up to November in a style that fits your groups and issues?</p>
    </html>
  </story>

  <story>
    <label>How We Build It: Flood the System Organizing Plan</label>
    <region
      x="0.23821"
      y="0.23271"
      width="0.41242"
      height="0.18429"
    />
    <html>
      <p>At the core of Flood the System is you and your friends, groups, and organizations. Your choices and your needs will affect what your actions will look like. Actions will look and feel different in different places, but this variety is exactly what makes up the Flood. </p>

      <p>This picture shows a flowing water system. It's a useful metaphor for how we intend to channel our growing numbers from isolated trickles into a powerful river that has the potential create great change. <strong>This part is all about smaller stuff flowing into bigger stuff.</strong> That’s what we mean by escalation.</p>

      <p><a href="https://risingtidenorthamerica.org/">Rising Tide North America (RTNA)</a> is committed to supporting groups to develop local structures and plans that can help them fit into Flood the System in ways that make sense. This organizing structure is meant to help weave together the different organizations and actions that will be taking part in Flood the System across the continent. </p>
    </html>
  </story>

    <story>
    <label>Watershed Gatherings</label>
      <region
        x="0.24403"
        y="0.24052"
        width="0.08936"
        height="0.05605"
      />
    <html>
      <p>Organizer gatherings are turning points and moments of confluence as we build towards the Flood. Trainings, summits, and public events build alignment, analysis, creativity, and capacity for individuals, organizations, and new groups.</p>

      <p>Real watersheds are area or ridges of land that separate waters flowing to different rivers, basins, or seas. They are the place within which all waters flow together. Here, we see tiny rivulets and trickles of brooks and creeks scaling up to flowing currents as they meet and merge, symbolizing the amplification of our campaigns, organizations, and messages we get when we join forces with our neighbors.</p>

      <p>We are looking for anchor groups to host regional Watershed gatherings. If this could include you or your organization, please let us know by emailing <a href="info@floodthesystem.net">info@floodthesystem.net</a>. </p>
    </html>
  </story>

    <story>
      <label>Coordination Streams</label>
      <region
        x="0.27152"
        y="0.29075"
        width="0.13906"
        height="0.05287"
      />
      <html>
        Watershed gatherings will lead to ongoing regional coordination, which we've drawn here as streams. Most likely, this will look like occasional regional conference calls, like the ones that already happen for the MidAtlantic and Northwest regions. It can also look like thematic coordination processes, like student activist networks across the country coordinating their Flood actions through a streamlining process of calls and coordination. Streams align and connect our work.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Action Councils: Pools of People</label>
      <region
        x="0.35876"
        y="0.26061"
        width="0.22260"
        height="0.06609"
      />
      <html>
        <p>Flood the System promotes <strong>action councils</strong> as the basic unit of organizing because they are emergent, horizontal, democratic, participatory, and scalable structures that support broad-based, grassroots coordination.</p>

        <p>Here, we see three different “pools” flowing into the regional stream that eventually connects to the continental coordinating body, the River Council. Each pool has concentric rings inside it, which reflects the organizing structure of an action council where a small group (the coordination team) facilitates a larger group (the spokespeople, who are like delegates to the action council), who in turn represent a larger group (all of the members of the groups the delegates represent) who in turn may turn out or coordinate an even larger network.</p>

        <p>In some places, folks may decide to organize a city-wide Action Council. In other places, a larger geographic area may want to coordinate a single action. Action Councils can also be formed with existing networks of people doing similar work that spreads beyond local or regional geographic lines, such as students doing a coordinated action at the same time across the US and Canada. But the North American continent is huge, and RTNA is small. If you think there should be a regional or thematic council that doesn’t exist yet, we definitely need your help making it happen.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The River Council</label>
      <region
        x="0.32387"
        y="0.32988"
        width="0.28394"
        height="0.07297"
      />
      <html>
        <p>The central coordinating body for Flood the System is the continental spokescouncil, or River Council. The River Council is made up of representatives from action councils that have formed across the continent, as well as representatives of working groups that are tasked with coordinating different pieces of the Flood the System work. The hope is that the needs, strategy and vision of as many local groups as possible will be represented in the River Council. </p>

        <p>Here the distinct currents of water in the riverbed are aligned and flowing towards the same goal. The River Council doesn’t set strategy, dictate policy, or tell local groups how to take action in their contexts. The River streamlines our work by coordinating it, supporting it, and helping us learn from each other. </p>

        <h4>Working Groups</h4>

        <p>Any members of local action councils are welcome and encouraged to participate in continental River Council Working Groups. These Working Groups provide logistical support for Flood the System. Working Groups are populated by folks in local action councils, as well as individuals who are super awesome at a specific area of work.</p>

        <p>Because Flood the System originated as a project from Rising Tide North America (RTNA), much of the organizing for Flood the System has been incubated by folks within the RTNA network. As we build the Flood, and more people become involved, the work will live in the hands of the people taking action. </p>

        <p>RTNA has been, since its inception in 2006, an all-volunteer network. After taking on this project, we decided to stipend two organizers to coordinate, push forward and support Flood the System organizing -- Sandy Nurse and Ahmed Gaya. Sandy is based in Brooklyn, New York and organizes with Rising Tide NYC. Sandy is helping to support groups in the Gulf South and along the East Coast. You can reach her at <a href="sandy@floodthesystem.net">sandy@floodthesystem.net</a>. Ahmed Gaya is based in Seattle and works with Rising Tide Seattle and the sHell No! Action Council. Ahmed is helping support groups on the West Coast and in the Midwest. He can be reached at <a href="ahmed@floodthesystem.net">ahmed@floodthesystem.net</a>. </p>

      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>What: People in Action</label>
      <region
        x="0.57833"
        y="0.18799"
        width="0.34448"
        height="0.16084"
      />
      <html>
        <p>Throughout the summer and the fall, local action councils and the continental River Council will coordinate our many organizing streams into a robust current that will build throughout the fall into a Flood of people in motion. Imagine small groups across the continent engaging in escalated actions, creating the energy, excitement and space for mass actions that target roots of injustice, like government and corporate headquarters, police stations, detention centers, and fossil fuel extraction, pipelines and rail lines. </p>

        <p>We’ve drawn this escalation as two graphics: the smaller rapid and the big Flood. The rapid is folding back on itself, while the Flood is outward facing. Both Rapid and Flood actions are critical to the success of Flood the System -- and so it’s up to you, your groups, and your action council to make the call about which kind of action (or both!) you’ll make happen, and this depends entirely on what kinds of escalation will serve to build your local work. We see the rapids actions as integral in the first part of the fall to build the momentum to make the flood actions possible.</p>

        <p>You can also see that the big tidal flood wave recedes and then prepares for another upswing. We know that we can’t continue an upsurge of energy forever. There will be a low tide after the Flood that will be a crucial time for reflection, rest, celebration, recovery, absorption of new people and ideas, and organizational growth. Then,  we’ll regroup and plan together for the high tide of our next work. Flood the System is just the beginning of a longer process to build a deeper, stronger movement. </p>

        <h4>Things to Keep in Mind While Organizing</h4>

        <p><strong>Training:</strong> We are asking all local action councils to identify folks within their circles who have some action experience and would like to participate in a Flood the System <strong>Training for Trainers</strong> sometime in late summer or early fall. These trainers will then be available to your council and Flood action to train up new folks who want to participate in your action. Our goal is to have actions be direct confrontations to the systems of power, occupations, sit-ins, shutdowns, and we want to make the spaces as safe as we can within the boundaries of actions that might have an element of risk. We believe that mass trainings are an important organizing tool to bringing new people into Flood the System.</p>

        <p><strong>Legal Support:</strong> The River Council can help troubleshoot legal support, but building a secure support structure for folks to participate in action is a local need, and should be done by each local action council. The National Lawyers Guild, the ACLU, and local legal collectives (if you have them) can all help answer legal questions and support activists that are engaging in civil disobedience and direct action and could face arrest. At the very least, they are good places to start building your local legal support network. </p>

        <p><strong>Arts and Culture:</strong> In your action council, you’re going to have tons of conversation about what you want the action to communicate, but when it comes down to it, a big chunk of how the event looks and feels rests on a handful of things: what the banners and signs that people carry say and look like, what people sing and chant, how we arrange ourselves in space, what pictures we take and share of the action. At any moment your group is doing outreach or recruitment, think about asking painters, musicians, dancers, poets, DJ’s, etc. you know if they want to be involved. A key to unleashing the awesomeness is inviting people to the table early who are there to think about the role of creativity. They might come up with some bizarre ideas that are totally the wrong thing for your plan...but they might just be the right ones, too. If you’re not sure where to start, think about what arts institutions might be in your region that you could reach out to for contacts or support, and feel free to reach out to the Arts and Culture working group at <a href="artsandculture@floodthesystem.net">artsandculture@floodthesystem.net</a> for help thinking through a recruitment strategy!</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Rapid Actions</label>
      <region
        x="0.57326"
        y="0.22345"
        width="0.14311"
        height="0.12665"
      />
      <html>
        <p>Here we can see a burst of energy, with water churning and reaching and swirling back on itself. Rapid actions are those that help us collectively escalate this fall. They can be held by any organization or affinity group that claims affinity with Flood the System and commits to the guiding principles. Rapid actions can occur at any time, anywhere that makes sense for you and your organizations. Taken collectively, these actions help tell a story of the breadth of injustices we are facing and of people who are fed up with it. As these actions begin to pop up across the continent, they help build excitement, energy, and awareness of the coming Flood later in the Fall.</p> 

        <p>If you are developing or executing rapid actions, it might be a good idea to coordinate with your local action council to make sure your allies are aware of the action, even if they don't have all the details and are not actively participating in the creation of the action itself.</p> 

        <p>If you are planning a rapid action and want it to be part of Flood the System, please feel free to let us know by contacting our Media Working Group at <a href="Media@floodthesystem.net">Media@floodthesystem.net</a></p>.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>Flood Actions</label>
      <region
        x="0.69358"
        y="0.18546"
        width="0.22163"
        height="0.14564"
      />
      <html>
        <p>Here we see a bigger wave -- our flood actions, the core of Flood the System and the high point of our planning. This wave is only possible because the rapid actions before it have created the momentum and energy for a larger wave. It is also only possible because of the energy generated from streams flowing into a river, the months of local planning, the process of working together and building new relationships.</p>

        <p>Because flood actions are big, they will require the coordination of a local action council and probably multiple groups. Like rapid actions, flood actions may occur at any time but we hope that action councils will orient their Flood action to be a part of the November push to mark the building momentum across the continent.</p>

        <p>Our vision is for Flood actions to be mass, participatory direct actions that target a central element of injustice in our system. Flood actions could also be sustained action taken by affinity groups as well. The targets will be different for different communities, and each council will make its own strategic decisions. It could be a government building or capital, it might be a rail line or pipeline or fossil fuel extraction site, or it could be the financial district, a police station, an immigrant detention center, or a jail in your community. We hope that local councils will be able to find targets appropriate to their work, but which also act as direct or symbolic spaces that represent the systemic problems we face. What Flood actions look or feel like is up to local councils.</p>

        <p>Because action councils have representation on the continental River Council, the Flood actions that local councils develop will have the support of the entire Flood the System network. Media and outreach for Flood actions can be coordinated both by the local action council as well as at the continental level through the outreach that's been done as a part of Flood the System more broadly (the River Council is building a large list of folks across the continent that want to be a part of Flood actions!). Because we want to include a lot of people in the actions themselves, we ask that the local organizers think about and create space for the involvement of many people. The River Council can support and advertise your Flood action, but the logistics and the design are yours to develop.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Low Tide</label>
      <region
        x="0.67331"
        y="0.33237"
        width="0.24063"
        height="0.07979"
      />
      <html>
        <p>After a large wave, there is a natural recession, a receding of the tide. This happens in our movements too. We have both big crests of energy when we are moving in sync together and then recessions where we can reflect and reorient. Both are important, and we need to remember that both are part of the movement building processes.  </p>

        <p>After the Flood, we know we'll retreat for a period of rest and reflection. We will gather with our groups and communities and have space to celebrate our successes and unpack the hardships. This is a time for sharing visions and making choices about how to move forward together. This is also the space for organizational building! We need to think about ways to absorb the momentum and enthusiasm we create so when we move into the next high tide we will be stronger and more prepared. </p>

        <p>Our low tide is an important part of the Flood the System because we know that we are starting a process. One goal of Flood the System is to, well, Flood the System in the Fall. It's concrete and action specific. Another goal of Flood the System is to create lasting movement infrastructure like action councils that continue on beyond the Flood. These action councils might contract during the low tide, but we intend to organize with the intention that they will last far beyond 2015. </p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>High Tide</label>
      <region
        x="0.89241"
        y="0.21585"
        width="0.10258"
        height="0.17224"
      />
      <html>
        <p>What will we do tomorrow that we are unable to do today? Our hope is that Flood the System gets us a little closer to all the many possible directions we can go. Here we see our wave starting to crest again in many different directions, all stronger streams than when they started. </p>

        <p>During the organizing process of Flood the System, we will be initiating conversations about what the next step is with local and regional action councils and groups. Obviously, the movement doesn't end with the conference in Paris. RTNA is not under the illusion that Flood the System is going to be the singular thing that washes away the entire system. We think by coordinating this wave, we can build stronger relationships and communication channels that allow us to decide on the next High Tide together.  </p>

        <p>Every low tide and high tide is part of a movement building cycle that allows us to grow stronger and bolder with each successive surge. During the build up to the flood, we should all be thinking about how we move forward. Let's practice being visionary and strategic in our targeting, and bold in our tactics and solidarity. What could an even stronger movement look like in 2016?</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Join the Flood</label>
      <region
        x="0.23077"
        y="0.02218"
        width="0.69615"
        height="0.39744"
      />
      <html>
        <p>The core of Flood the System is people organizing together for a better world. Where do you see yourself in the Flood? Are you working with a group to do a rapids action? Are you organizing a group to go to a Flood action in your area? Are you already part of a group organizing or campaigning? Are you an artist, a musician, or a creative person?</p>

        <p>We know that this call for movement momentum this year is lofty. We also know that there are thousands of people across the continent looking for opportunities to push together. </p>

        <p>If you’d like to get involved in building the Flood, here are some ways:</p>

        <h4>Let folks know about the Flood!</h4>

        <p>Please promote the idea, the literature, the website, and the presence on social media! We want this idea spread far and wide, talk about it within your network, share it with your friends, help spread the word! If you’re interested in helping with presenting about Flood the System, email training@floodthesystem.net</p>

        <ul>
          <li>Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/floodthesystem">#Floodthesystem</a></li>
          <li>Website: <a href="http://floodthesystem.net">floodthesystem.net</a></li>
          <li>Facebook: <a href="http://bit.ly/floodthesystem">bit.ly/floodthesystem</a></li>
          <li>Online Booklet PDF: <a href="floodthesystem.net">floodthesystem.net</a></li>
        </ul>

        <h4>Participate in a Flood training or action!</h4>

        <p>If you are just looking to attend an FTS training or action in the fall, sign up online at <a href="http://floodthesystem.net">floodthesystem.net</a> and let us know that that's what you want to do. The River Council and RTNA will send you information about upcoming actions, Watershed Summits, and trainings in your area so you can get prepared to Flood the System!</p>

        <h4>Hold a Rapid action!</h4>

        <p>Rapid actions are key parts of Flooding the System. They provide momentum, and give voice to local struggles. Any group can hold a rapid action at any time or tie in an existing action as part of Flood the System as long as it supports the principles. Out tools are yours to use. </p>

        <p>If you are planning Rapid actions and want them to be a part of Flood the System please let our media working group know so we can make sure we get the info out there!! We are collaborating with artists and cultural workers to create graphics, images, presentations and replicable art for FTS Flood and Rapid actions. Please use them!!</p>

        <h4>Plug your affinity group, organization, church group, or community organization into the planning process!</h4>

        <p>Joining the organizing process for a Flood action or local action council is easy! You may have already heard of work in your area and that's great. If not, and you might want to plug your group into the action council organizing process or attend a Watershed summit let us know via our online sign-up process and we can direct you to the local work in your region.</p>

        <h4>If you want to get involved with the Continental Working Groups, here’s some contact information for you!</h4>

        <ul>
          <li>Arts and Culture Continental Working Group: <a href="mailto:artsandculture@floodthesystem.net">artsandculture@floodthesystem.net</a></li>
          <li>Trainings Continental Working Group: <a href="mailto:training@floodthesystem.net">training@floodthesystem.net</a></li>
          <li>Media Continental Working Group: <a href="mailto:media@floodthesystem.net">media@floodthesystem.net</a></li>
          <li>General Questions: <a href="mailto:info@floodthesystem.net">info@floodthesystem.net</a></li>
          <li>For organizing in the Midwest, Southwest, Rockies, West Coast, Western Canada, contact Ahmed: <a href="mailto:ahmed@floodthesystem.net">ahmed@floodthesystem.net</a></li>
          <li>For organizing in the Gulf South, South, Mid-Atlantic, Northeast, Eastern Canada, contact Sandy: <a href="mailto:sandy@floodthesystem.net">sandy@floodthesystem.net</a></li>
        </ul>


      </html>
    </story>
  </stories>
</data>
