<data>
  <title>
      Mesoamérica Resiste (Front) from the Beehive Design Collective
  </title>
  <link>
    http://beehivecollective.org/beehive_poster/mesoamerica-resiste/
  </link>

  <stories>  



    <story>
      <label>The Colonizers' view</label>
      <region
        x="0"
        y="0"
        width="1.0"
        height="1.0"
      />
      <html>
        This poster folds to create a square with shutters that open to a larger image inside. With the shutters closed, the outside of the poster resembles an old Spanish conquistador’s map
        of Mesoamerica. The map is a top-down look at the region and
        draws parallels between colonial history and modern-day capitalism. Outsiders who have no connection with the land have drawn this map, with motives of extraction and profit.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The Land Bridge</label>
      <region
        x="0.29332"
        y="0.37626"
        width="0.31297"
        height="0.29643"
      />
      <html>
        <p>Mesoamerica is a cultural and geographic region that forms a thin land bridge (or isthmus) between North and South America and the Atlantic and Pacific Oceans—making this region highly strategic for international trade. Due
        to its climate and geography, Mesoamerica is one of the most biodiverse
        areas on the planet.
        </p>
        <p>Mega-development projects and extractive industries spell a
        death sentence for the ecosystems
        and land-based communities of the region.
        </p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Paving the Way for Free Trade</label>
          <region
            x="0.23901"
            y="0.41110"
            width="0.22967"
            height="0.14958"
          />
      <html>
        <p>Since the invasion of Hernán Cortes’ metal-clad armies in 1519, a long succession of foreign colonizers and transnational corporations have occupied and exploited Mesoamerica. Corporations and the U.S. State have referred to Mexico and Central America as their “backyard” since the early 1800s. Now with free trade agreements working to eliminate so many “barriers” to trade (like environmental and labor rights, industry is all the more eager to develop infrastructure in Mesoamerica to exploit the region</p>
        <p>In 2001 the president of Mexico and the Interamerican Development Bank introduced a plan to literally pave the way for implementing free trade policies. Named Plan Puebla Panama (PPP), the original plan included the southern states of Mexico (from Puebla) and the countries of Central America (to Panama). After fierce opposition throughout the region, the PPP underwent a public relations makeover and in 2008 was renamed the Mesoamerican Integration and Development Project, or Project Mesoamerica. The plan now includes Colombia and the Dominican Republic.</p>

      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Project Mesoamerica</label>
      <region
        x="0.23897"
        y="0.22177"
        width="0.10508"
        height="0.06461"
      />
      <html>
        <p>Project Mesoamerica consists of 8 initiatives to “strengthen regional integration and promote economic and social development,” but the bulk of the funding is going towards large-scale infrastructure projects for transportation, to increase “market competitiveness” by moving high volumes of commerce through the region. These highways, ports, and canals connect with factory zones, mines and resource extraction sites, and large-scale energy projects that power it all.</p>
        <p>These plans are unfolding in the context of the expanding War on Drugs, which has led to dramatically increased violence and further militarization of the U.S./Mexico border.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Compass Rose</label>
      <region
        x="0.24492"
        y="0.64254"
        width="0.14654"
        height="0.14825"
      />
      <html>
        <p>The compass rose, flanked by capitalist
        mermaids, orients us to this map of the
        global economy.</p>
        <p>The compass is a roulette wheel where corporations recklessly
        gamble with the future of the region, the ball bouncing over the logos of foreign investors who are steering local economies towards
export. Railroads and tanks circle the game, reminding us
of the violent history of the United Fruit Company (now Chiquita) in Central America: controlling large tracts of land, repressing workers, and even supporting a coup that led to decades of dictatorship in Guatemala, overthrowing a democratically elected president who tried to redistribute land to the people.</p>
        <p>The banana and coffee industries have benefited from the use of military force and violence to take control of some of the most arable land—in order to produce breakfast products for the global North.</p>
        
      </html>
    </story>

     <story>
      <label>The Trade Winds: The North Cloud</label>
      <region
        x="0.30339"
        y="0.09500"
        width="0.26909"
        height="0.20080"
      />
      <html>
        <p>On all sides of the map, weather systems illustrate the global forces exerting pressure on the region.</p>
        <p>A dark cloud from the
North puts high pressure
on the world as it creates
a storm of violence. This
pressure system is the driving
force behind military invasions and the War on Drugs, global economic policies, corporate interests and consumerism. Pushing these agendas forward, the cloud rains down military violence, weapons, pollution, pesticides, and cultural invasion.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The Trade Winds: The Hurricane in the South</label>
      <region
        x="0.38660"
        y="0.72818"
        width="0.22805"
        height="0.11814"
      />
      <html>
        A hurricane of unnatural disasters rips through the southern hemisphere, devastating already marginalized communities and reminding us that we’re
not “all in this together.” Though industrialized countries in the global North are causing this climate chaos, the first and worst impacts of climate change are being felt by the global South. Governments and corporations are finding ways to profit from increasingly frequent severe storms and weather, a form of “disaster capitalism” that takes advantage of crises as
opportunities to push through their economic agendas.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>In the East: The typhoon of mass production</label>
       <region
        x="0.10538"
        y="0.47446"
        width="0.15396"
        height="0.19159"
      />
      <html>
        The blind face of expanding production appears as a typhoon at sea. The stormfront steamrolls forward as a dark cloud wall, spilling out cheap parts filling endless rows of containers destined for the trade routes cutting through Mesoamerica.        
      </html>
    </story>


     <story>
      <label>In the West: The whirlwind of disposable consumerism</label>
       <region
        x="0.60186"
        y="0.23126"
        width="0.23877"
        height="0.27264"
      />
      <html>
        The insatiable appetite for disposable goods controls the West wind. Sucking
        up container ships from the East Wind and spitting out a trash barge, the Consumer Vortex in the West creates a tornado of swirling detritus. Demand from North America and Europe, combined with accelerating mass manufacturing in East
        and South Asia, exerts intense pressure to open up more passages through the isthmus of Central America.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>Colonialism past &amp; present</label>
      <region
        x="0.35464"
        y="0.25794"
        width="0.34283"
        height="0.22944"
      />
      <html>
        <p>Modern industrial cargo boats morphed with ships from the “Age of Expansion” sail across the map, some hauling away cash crops and others bringing imports.</p>
        <p>Three of these ships tell the story of the Triangle Trade of the late 1500s to early 1800s, the Atlantic Slave Trade circuit that relied on trafficking gold, sugar, and humans. Rum, made from sugar, was moved across the ocean to Africa and used to corrupt local leaders into facilitating the slave hunt. European colonists then shipped enslaved peoples to the sugar plantations in the Caribbean, where sugar was picked up and sent to Europe (and New England) to
        turn into rum, completing the triangle.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The Gold boat</label>
      <region
        x="0.60318"
        y="0.25825"
        width="0.09508"
        height="0.09679"
      />
      <html>
        The Gold boat has a full trunk of precious metals stolen from the Americas. It melts down culturally meaningful metalwork into bars of gold, and
        is propelled by the sails of modern
        banks, which continue this legacy of accumulating wealth
        through systems of oppression.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The Sugar boat</label>
      <region
        x="0.51708"
        y="0.27866"
        width="0.09977"
        height="0.12499"
      />
      <html>
        Led by King Kool-Aid, the Sugar boat scoops piles of sugar into our food with its oars and
        relies on wage slavery to produce sugar cheaply while maintaining high profits. 
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The slave ship</label>
      <region
        x="0.58048"
        y="0.37080"
        width="0.11103"
        height="0.08007"
      />
      <html>
        The slave ship, with its crows nest guard towers and
        security cameras, connects the legacy of slavery to the modern
        prison system, which heavily incarcerates and surveilles communities of color in North America.
      </html>
    </story>



    <story>
      <label>Cash crops for export</label>
      <region
        x="0.42853"
        y="0.38736"
        width="0.17483"
        height="0.18335"
      />
      <html>
        Some of the ships carry natural resources out of the region, from precious fresh water to oil reserves.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>The beef boat</label>
      <region
        x="0.37741"
        y="0.62080"
        width="0.13802"
        height="0.14859"
      />
      <html>
        The beef boat has a clear-cut in tow, a reminder of the massive deforestation caused by cattle ranching.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>A heavily loaded mining ship</label>
      <region
        x="0.64975"
        y="0.51889"
        width="0.11095"
        height="0.11842"
      />
      <html>
        A heavily loaded mining ship that resembles a dump truck departs from Central America, its sails carrying the logos of
        just two of the many Canadian mining companies
        operating in the
        region. Canada is the #1 holder of mining
        concessions around the world, and home to some of the worst environmental
        offenders and human rights violators in the mining sector.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>A drug trafficking boat</label>
      <region
        x="0.73623"
        y="0.53054"
        width="0.08264"
        height="0.14132"
      />
      <html>
        Near the Colombian coast, a drug trafficking boat armed with hypodermic needles speeds away with its illicit cargo. Not far behind, the CIA's money laundering machine is a reference to the CIA’s direct involvement in profiting off the drug trade.

      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The fishing boat</label>
      <region
        x="0.19724"
        y="0.59583"
        width="0.11727"
        height="0.11325"
      />
      <html>
        ￼A reminder that over-extraction of resources is not only happening on land, the fishing boat’s enormous net scoops up every sea creature in its path.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The illegal animal trade boat</label>
      <region
        x="0.57304"
        y="0.71188"
        width="0.13212"
        height="0.12467"
      />
      <html>
        The illegal animal trade boat ferries out exotic
      local animals, caught by poachers after infrastructure projects and deforesta- tion displaced these endangered creatures from their native habitat.
      </html>
    </story>

      <story>
      <label>Coming in from the North</label>
      <region
        x="0.54693"
        y="0.17321"
        width="0.07952"
        height="0.13603"
      />
      <html>        
        While the local animals are exported away, cartoon animals come in to replace them. Icons of mass media and consumer culture sail the seas on a Coca-Cola bottle.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>A gun ship</label>
      <region
        x="0.33306"
        y="0.27377"
        width="0.11170"
        height="0.11999"
      />
      <html>
        A gun ship carried in by by the storm cloud in the North brings military aid in the form of
        weapons wrapped up with a bow.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Another ship carries toxic chemical imports</label>
      <region
        x="0.25601"
        y="0.27427"
        width="0.11222"
        height="0.10887"
      />
      <html>
        Close by another ship carries toxic chemical imports, equipped with a runway
        for the crop duster planes used to spray pesticides and herbicides on tropical fruit export crops.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>International Financial Instiutions</label>
      <region
        x="0"
        y="0"
        width="1.0"
        height="1.0"
      />
      <html>
        In the corners of the map, four faceless characters are in control from behind the scenes: a conqueror, a doctor (of the economy), a judge and a gambling banker.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>International Development Bank</label>
      <region
        x="0.00152"
        y="0.00190"
        width="0.26522"
        height="0.27462"
      />
      <html>
        Drawn as a Spanish conquistador, the IDB is the initial and biggest
        financier of Project Mesoamerica and is the regional arm of the World
        Bank. Gas lines, oil pipelines, and toll highways flow from the cash
        ￼register drawer of the IDB. The face of the register shows one Free Trade Agreement rolling into the next, cashing in on the elimination of barriers to the “open market” in North and Central America. The IDB relies on its finger-puppet governments to shake down the public 
        (paper dolls) to pay the interest on loans. The BCIE (Central American Bank for Economic Integration) serves as an ATM to supply cash for more publicly unpopular projects, chained to the IDB like a bulldog because of its more aggressive approach to lending.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>International Monetary Fund</label>
      <region
        x="0.00103"
        y="0.67422"
        width="0.27066"
        height="0.32648"
      />
      <html>
        When a country’s economy is in crisis, the IMF is called in to give bailout loans to use to
        pay the interest on existing debt. It implements Structural
        Adjustment Programs (SAPS) that tie harsh conditions to these new loans. In the operating
        room, the IMF is gutting public services and applying leeches as a reference to
        how it uses SAPS to suck the life out of the public sector
        and force them into even higher interest payments. Dam-defibrillators apply “shock therapy” to the economy
        and keep the patient (Mesoamerica) pinned to the surgeon’s table. The syringe is symbolic of IMF conditions that open up the economy to extraction.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>WTO - The World Trade Organization</label>
       <region
        x="0.69956"
        y="0.01685"
        width="0.28933"
        height="0.25457"
      />
      <html>
        <p>The World Trade Organization serves as a judge of international trade disputes, favoring corporate interests at the expense of workers and the environment. The crumbling institution holds
        scales of injustice,
        protecting the interests of the 1% while
        leaving the people of
        the world to hang.</p>
        <p>A riot
        cop puppet tries to crack down on anti-globalization protesters in a game of whack-a-mole, but their diverse tactics allow them to continue popping up.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The World Bank</label>
      <region
        x="0.68870"
        y="0.68725"
        width="0.30862"
        height="0.31605"
      />
      <html>        
        The World Bank, another
        important lending institution behind Project Mesoamerica, is portrayed as a
        potbellied gambler, addicted
        to the fossil fuel economy.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>The Clean
        Development Mechanism</label>
      <region
        x="0.55759"
        y="0.80006"
        width="0.22782"
        height="0.17671"
      />
      <html>
        The World Bank is responsible in part for the Clean
        Development Mechanism
        (CDM), shown as a shady coin-operated chess game that the Bank plays with itself. The Clean Development Mechanism (CDM) allows dirty industry to get credits for building ‘green’
        projects in the global South. The credits are said to “offset” pollution without making industries cut back on polluting activities. Bulldozers and excavators push all the chess pieces out of their path, regardless of whether they’re on the “dirty” or “clean” energy side of the
        game. 
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>The house always wins</label>
      <region
        x="0.77967"
        y="0.73327"
        width="0.18108"
        height="0.20121"
      />
      <html>
        The World Bank pours dollars into the carbon market by cutting out coins from a cloud of smoke while its other arm plays the slot machines, taking its chances with natural disasters. On the poker table in front of the Bank, the chips are stacked up against the global South. With loans tied to conditions like economic bear traps, the house always wins.        
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Greenwashing</label>
      <region
        x="0.38347"
        y="0.81432"
        width="0.23508"
        height="0.16820"
      />
      <html>
        Major extractive
        industries sit at a
        boardroom table
        and cut up a cake in
        the shape of Mesoamerica, honoring
        500 years of colonialism. Trying to
        appear harmless in
        their animal disguises, these greenwashed industry representatives steal natural resources from Mesoamerica, as they hustle a small sampling of biodiversity onto Noah’s Ark.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The biosphere reserve</label>
     <region
        x="0.21041"
        y="0.82874"
        width="0.20758"
        height="0.15557"
      />
      <html>
        <p>Under the guise of conservation, the biosphere reserve nearby appears as a guarded greenhouse - particularly referring to the Mesoamerican Biological Corridor, a project of the World Bank. This private-sector approach to conservation leads to evictions of Indigenous communities who have long been stewards of the land, while allowing industry to access “protected” areas for activities
        including oil prospecting. </p>
        <p>Eager for a photo op to
        try to improve their public image, the greenwashers hold up a false backdrop to attract visitors and investors from afar.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>El Campo Sin Campesino</label>
      <region
        x="0.01284"
        y="0.22262"
        width="0.12484"
        height="0.06528"
      />
      <html>
      <p>At the top of this cycle, a communally-farmed beehive is broken up
      into small hexagons.
      The Department of Agriculture and the Bank join forces
      to push for individual land titles and credit to
      finance this dismantling of collective and Indigenous lands.</p>
      <p>In 1992, anticipating the signing of NAFTA, the Mexican government changed its constitution to allow for the privatization of communal lands; a decade later, Central
      American countries faced the same privatization
      with the signing of CAFTA-DR.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Farmer Bee brings her corn to market</label>
      <region
        x="0.08705"
        y="0.24898"
        width="0.08201"
        height="0.10217"
      />
      <html>
        <p>After a long and hard season working her little hexagon plot, Farmer Bee brings her corn to market, but her corn doesn’t measure up.</p>

        <p>Free trade policies have opened the borders to dumping of cheaply produced corn from the
        United States, and Farmer Bee can’t compete with prices set by an open market flooded with grain from subsidized, large-scale agriculture.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The bank comes to collect the interest on her land</label>
      <region
        x="0.01764"
        y="0.31180"
        width="0.12592"
        height="0.13114"
      />
      <html>
        <p>When the bank comes to collect the interest on her land, she must break the bank, sell her
        land and join the many other economic refugees headed to the city to look for work.
        </p>
        <p>Farmer Bee takes one of the
        only jobs available, in a maquiladora (sweatshop), where she works in unsafe conditions for low wages.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The sewing machines in the maquiladora</label>
      <region
        x="0.00834"
        y="0.43399"
        width="0.11195"
        height="0.17196"
      />
      <html>
        The sewing machines in the maquiladora are sucking
        up traditional textiles and
        spitting out a line of mass-produced brand name clothing
        to flood the shopping malls of the global marketplace. 
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The mall</label>
      <region
        x="0.00913"
        y="0.51035"
        width="0.14683"
        height="0.16159"
      />
      <html>
        The mall has
        replaced
        the
        church as
        the new center of worship in town.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Looking deeper</label>
      <region
        x="0.05315"
        y="0.57538"
        width="0.12439"
        height="0.13717"
      />
      <html>
        Looking deeper, we see that the church was built directly on top of a Mayan pyramid, a literal reference to colonial history.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>Meanwhile, the de-populated rural areas…</label>
      <region
        x="0.01083"
        y="0.26895"
        width="0.09684"
        height="0.09429"
      />
      <html>
        Meanwhile, the de-populated rural areas have been bought
        up for monocultures of
        cash crops and extractive
        energy projects.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Crossing the border to find work</label>
      <region
        x="0.10896"
        y="0.34961"
        width="0.07218"
        height="0.12827"
      />
      <html>
        Through
        this cycle of
        displacement, some
        of the bees risk their lives crossing the border to find work. They disappear off to the north, maybe never to be heard from again.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The Quetzal bird</label>
      <region
        x="0.09665"
        y="0.65443"
        width="0.12496"
        height="0.12425"
      />
      <html>
        The Quetzal bird holds on to the social fabric of communities and steadily weaves cultural resistance, keeping alive textile traditions and the art of communicating through patterns and drawings.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Resistance and Repression</label>
      <region
        x="0.80873"
        y="0.21657"
        width="0.17490"
        height="0.22849"
      />
      <html>
        <p>On the right side of the map,
        swarms of ants rise and fall
        in a cycle of resistance and repression. Troops force ants into
        a mass grave and firebomb their
        crops and villages, a direct reference to the scorched earth policy
        of the military dictatorship in Guatemala in the early 1980s, a genocide
        campaign that specifically targeted
        the Ixil Maya people.</p>
        <p>Guatemala’s civil war is emblematic of the entire region’s history, stemming from a long history of land grabs, inequality, racism, and U.S. intervention. Rising up from below, social movements continue to regroup and carry on struggles against militarization and for land reform, sovereignty, and justice, even when faced with the trauma of state brutality, mass arrests, and forced disappearances.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>A new form of violence against people
        and the land</label>
      <region
        x="0.76748"
        y="0.42075"
        width="0.21947"
        height="0.10360"
      />
      <html>
        A tank-tractor merges the war machine with industrial agriculture, a new form of violence against people
        and the land. After World War
        II, factories that made tanks
        and explosives for war were put to new
        use and started pumping out tractors and fertilizers instead, leading
        to the world-wide Green Revolution and corporate control of agriculture. A mother stalk of corn is being assaulted and violated by the tank-tractor, sprayed with GMO seed and a toxic medley of chemicals.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>A Trojan horse rolls in…</label>
      <region
          x="0.82269"
          y="0.49811"
          width="0.16767"
          height="0.12575"
        />
      <html>
        A Trojan horse rolls in, sponsored by big agribusinesses who claim to be the solution to world hunger. An army of genetically-modified corn charges out, ready to attack.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>“Corn”quistadors</label>
          <region
      x="0.80020"
      y="0.53219"
      width="0.12882"
      height="0.15199"
    />
      <html>
        <p>Like the Spanish conquistadors
        who used biological warfare,
        spreading disease to indigenous
        people of the Americas, these “corn”quistadors are destroying indigenous corn and food sovereignty with genetic contamination. One also wields
        a gas pump weapon as a reference to ethanol, an agrofuel from corn that is a false alternative to fossil fuels.</p>
        <p>Production of monocropped biofuels takes over huge swaths of land,
        depletes the soil, and contaminates water with fertilizers, while failing to address the consumption of fuel in the global North.</p>
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>The ants reemerge</label>
      <region
        x="0.88267"
        y="0.59013"
        width="0.09372"
        height="0.13155"
      />
      <html>
        Below it all, the ants reemerge again as a symbol of popular re- sistance. While they are protesting at the top of the scene, here they are busy tending to the life cycle of corn that feeds and sustains their community: sowing and saving seeds, exchanging local varieties, and grinding corn into flour.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>The Orb-weaver spider</label>
      <region
        x="0.75998"
        y="0.65113"
        width="0.14450"
        height="0.10871"
      />
      <html>
        <p>The Orb-weaver spider, mirroring the efforts of the Quetzal bird on the opposite side, painstakingly works on weaving topsoil back together and healing the land.</p>
        <p><a href="?poster=mr-inside&amp;lang=en">Continue on inside the poster <img src="./images/right.png" alt="" class="tiny-icon nav-next-icon" /></a></p>
      </html>
    </story>



  </stories>
</data>
