<?xml version="1.0"?>
<data>
  <title>
      Mesoam&#xE9;rica Resiste
      from the Beehive Design Collective
  </title>
  <link>
    http://beehivecollective.org/beehive_poster/mesoamerica-resiste/
  </link>

  <stories>  



    <story>
      <label class="subhead">The Colonizers' view</label>
      <region x="0.00000" y="0.00000" width="0.33333" height="0.33333"/>
      <html>
        <p>This poster folds to create a square with shutters that open to a larger image inside.</p>

        <p><img src="images/drawn-folding-MR.png" /></p>

        <p>With the shutters closed, the outside of the poster resembles an old Spanish conquistador&#x2019;s map
        of Mesoamerica. The map is a top-down look at the region and
        draws parallels between colonial history and modern-day capitalism. Outsiders who have no connection with the land have drawn this map, with motives of extraction and profit.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The Land Bridge</label>
      <region
        x="0.09284"
        y="0.12982"
        width="0.14597"
        height="0.10564"
      />
      <html>
        <p>Mesoamerica is a cultural and geographic region that forms a thin land bridge (or isthmus) between North and South America and the Atlantic and Pacific Oceans&#x2014;making this region highly strategic for international trade. Due
        to its climate and geography, Mesoamerica is one of the most biodiverse
        areas on the planet.
        </p>
        <p>Mega-development projects and extractive industries spell a
        death sentence for the ecosystems
        and land-based communities of the region.
        </p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Paving the Way for Free Trade</label>
      <region
        x="0.07322"
        y="0.11771"
        width="0.06759"
        height="0.06243"
      />
      <html>
        <p>Since the invasion of Hern&#xE1;n Cort&#xE9;s&#x2019; metal-clad armies in 1519, a long succession of foreign colonizers and transnational corporations have occupied and exploited Mesoamerica. Corporations and the U.S. State have referred to Mexico and Central America as their &#x201C;backyard&#x201D; since the early 1800s. Now with free trade agreements working to eliminate so many &#x201C;barriers&#x201D; to trade (like environmental and labor rights, industry is all the more eager to develop infrastructure in Mesoamerica to exploit the region</p>
        <p>In 2001 the president of Mexico and the Interamerican Development Bank introduced a plan to literally pave the way for implementing free trade policies. Named Plan Puebla Panama (PPP), the original plan included the southern states of Mexico (from Puebla) and the countries of Central America (to Panama). After fierce opposition throughout the region, the PPP underwent a public relations makeover and in 2008 was renamed the Mesoamerican Integration and Development Project, or Project Mesoamerica. The plan now includes Colombia and the Dominican Republic.</p>

      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Project Mesoamerica</label>
      <region
        x="0.06108"
        y="0.07381"
        width="0.05675"
        height="0.08927"
      />
      <html>
        <p>Project Mesoamerica consists of 8 initiatives to &#x201C;strengthen regional integration and promote economic and social development,&#x201D; but the bulk of the funding is going towards large-scale infrastructure projects for transportation, to increase &#x201C;market competitiveness&#x201D; by moving high volumes of commerce through the region. These highways, ports, and canals connect with factory zones, mines and resource extraction sites, and large-scale energy projects that power it all.</p>
        <p>These plans are unfolding in the context of the expanding War on Drugs, which has led to dramatically increased violence and further militarization of the U.S./Mexico border.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Compass Rose</label>
      <region
        x="0.08442"
        y="0.21401"
        width="0.04863"
        height="0.04369"
      />
      <html>
        <p>The compass rose, flanked by capitalist
        mermaids, orients us to this map of the
        global economy.</p>
        <p>The compass is a roulette wheel where corporations recklessly
        gamble with the future of the region, the ball bouncing over the logos of foreign investors who are steering local economies towards
export. Railroads and tanks circle the game, reminding us
of the violent history of the United Fruit Company (now Chiquita) in Central America: controlling large tracts of land, repressing workers, and even supporting a coup that led to decades of dictatorship in Guatemala, overthrowing a democratically elected president who tried to redistribute land to the people.</p>
        <p>The banana and coffee industries have benefited from the use of military force and violence to take control of some of the most arable land&#x2014;in order to produce breakfast products for the global North.</p>
        
      </html>
    </story>

     <story>
      <label>The Trade Winds: The North Cloud</label>
      <region
        x="0.10334"
        y="0.03469"
        width="0.09075"
        height="0.06273"
      />
      <html>
        <p>On all sides of the map, weather systems illustrate the global forces exerting pressure on the region.</p>
        <p>A dark cloud from the
North puts high pressure
on the world as it creates
a storm of violence. This
pressure system is the driving
force behind military invasions and the War on Drugs, global economic policies, corporate interests and consumerism. Pushing these agendas forward, the cloud rains down military violence, weapons, pollution, pesticides, and cultural invasion.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The Trade Winds: The Hurricane in the South</label>
      <region
        x="0.12870"
        y="0.23966"
        width="0.07999"
        height="0.03255"
      />
      <html>
        A hurricane of unnatural disasters rips through the southern hemisphere, devastating already marginalized communities and reminding us that we&#x2019;re
not &#x201C;all in this together.&#x201D; Though industrialized countries in the global North are causing this climate chaos, the first and worst impacts of climate change are being felt by the global South. Governments and corporations are finding ways to profit from increasingly frequent severe storms and weather, a form of &#x201C;disaster capitalism&#x201D; that takes advantage of crises as
opportunities to push through their economic agendas.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>In the East: The typhoon of mass production</label>
       <region
        x="0.03971"
        y="0.15625"
        width="0.05608"
        height="0.06255"
      />
      <html>
        The blind face of expanding production appears as a typhoon at sea. The stormfront steamrolls forward as a dark cloud wall, spilling out cheap parts filling endless rows of containers destined for the trade routes cutting through Mesoamerica.        
      </html>
    </story>


     <story>
      <label>In the West: The whirlwind of disposable consumerism</label>
      <region
        x="0.22613"
        y="0.07953"
        width="0.04619"
        height="0.07405"
      />
      <html>
        The insatiable appetite for disposable goods controls the West wind. Sucking
        up container ships from the East Wind and spitting out a trash barge, the Consumer Vortex in the West creates a tornado of swirling detritus. Demand from North America and Europe, combined with accelerating mass manufacturing in East
        and South Asia, exerts intense pressure to open up more passages through the isthmus of Central America.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>Colonialism past &amp; present</label>
      <region
        x="0.15571"
        y="0.08692"
        width="0.08399"
        height="0.07459"
      />
      <html>
        <p>Modern industrial cargo boats morphed with ships from the &#x201C;Age of Expansion&#x201D; sail across the map, some hauling away cash crops and others bringing imports.</p>
        <p>Three of these ships tell the story of the Triangle Trade of the late 1500s to early 1800s, the Atlantic Slave Trade circuit that relied on trafficking gold, sugar, and humans. Rum, made from sugar, was moved across the ocean to Africa and used to corrupt local leaders into facilitating the slave hunt. European colonists then shipped enslaved peoples to the sugar plantations in the Caribbean, where sugar was picked up and sent to Europe (and New England) to
        turn into rum, completing the triangle.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The Gold boat</label>
      <region
        x="0.19967"
        y="0.08579"
        width="0.03413"
        height="0.03446"
      />
      <html>
        The Gold boat has a full trunk of precious metals stolen from the Americas. It melts down culturally meaningful metalwork into bars of gold, and
        is propelled by the sails of modern
        banks, which continue this legacy of accumulating wealth
        through systems of oppression.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The Sugar boat</label>
      <region
        x="0.17064"
        y="0.09369"
        width="0.03430"
        height="0.03981"
      />
      <html>
        Led by King Kool-Aid, the Sugar boat scoops piles of sugar into our food with its oars and
        relies on wage slavery to produce sugar cheaply while maintaining high profits. 
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The slave ship</label>
      <region
        x="0.19079"
        y="0.12042"
        width="0.04343"
        height="0.03027"
      />
      <html>
        The slave ship, with its crows nest guard towers and
        security cameras, connects the legacy of slavery to the modern
        prison system, which heavily incarcerates and surveilles communities of color in North America.
      </html>
    </story>



    <story>
      <label>Cash crops for export</label>
      <region x="0.14284" y="0.12912" width="0.05828" height="0.06112"/>
      <html>
        Some of the ships carry natural resources out of the region, from precious fresh water to oil reserves.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>The beef boat</label>
      <region
        x="0.12537"
        y="0.20959"
        width="0.04737"
        height="0.04620"
      />
      <html>
        The beef boat has a clear-cut in tow, a reminder of the massive deforestation caused by cattle ranching.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>A heavily loaded mining ship</label>
      <region
        x="0.22364"
        y="0.16135"
        width="0.03385"
        height="0.05283"
      />
      <html>
        A heavily loaded mining ship that resembles a dump truck departs from Central America, its sails carrying the logos of
        just two of the many Canadian mining companies
        operating in the
        region. Canada is the #1 holder of mining
        concessions around the world, and home to some of the worst environmental
        offenders and human rights violators in the mining sector.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>A drug trafficking boat</label>
      <region
        x="0.24442"
        y="0.16854"
        width="0.03206"
        height="0.05155"
      />
      <html>
        Near the Colombian coast, a drug trafficking boat armed with hypodermic needles speeds away with its illicit cargo. Not far behind, the CIA's money laundering machine is a reference to the CIA&#x2019;s direct involvement in profiting off the drug trade.

      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The fishing boat</label>
      <region
        x="0.07007"
        y="0.19267"
        width="0.03699"
        height="0.04025"
      />
      <html>
        A reminder that over-extraction of resources is not only happening on land, the fishing boat&#x2019;s enormous net scoops up every sea creature in its path.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The illegal animal trade boat</label>
      <region
        x="0.19351"
        y="0.23678"
        width="0.04142"
        height="0.03652"
      />
      <html>
        The illegal animal trade boat ferries out exotic
      local animals, caught by poachers after infrastructure projects and deforesta- tion displaced these endangered creatures from their native habitat.
      </html>
    </story>

      <story>
      <label>Coming in from the North</label>
      <region
        x="0.18639"
        y="0.06107"
        width="0.02578"
        height="0.04072"
      />
      <html>        
        While the local animals are exported away, cartoon animals come in to replace them. Icons of mass media and consumer culture sail the seas on a Coca-Cola bottle.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>A gun ship</label>
      <region
        x="0.11272"
        y="0.09544"
        width="0.03475"
        height="0.04360"
      />
      <html>
        A gun ship carried in by by the storm cloud in the North brings military aid in the form of
        weapons wrapped up with a bow.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Another ship carries toxic chemical imports</label>
      <region
        x="0.09093"
        y="0.08967"
        width="0.03411"
        height="0.04232"
      />
      <html>
        Close by another ship carries toxic chemical imports, equipped with a runway
        for the crop duster planes used to spray pesticides and herbicides on tropical fruit export crops.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>International Financial Instiutions</label>
      <region x="0.00000" y="0.00000" width="0.33333" height="0.33333"/>
      <html>
        In the corners of the map, four faceless characters are in control from behind the scenes: a conqueror, a doctor (of the economy), a judge and a gambling banker.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>Inter-American Development Bank</label>
      <region x="0.00051" y="0.00063" width="0.08841" height="0.09154"/>
      <html>
        Drawn as a Spanish conquistador, the IDB is the initial and biggest
        financier of Project Mesoamerica and is the regional arm of the World
        Bank. Gas lines, oil pipelines, and toll highways flow from the cash register drawer of the IDB. The face of the register shows one Free Trade Agreement rolling into the next, cashing in on the elimination of barriers to the &#x201C;open market&#x201D; in North and Central America. The IDB relies on its finger-puppet governments to shake down the public 
        (paper dolls) to pay the interest on loans. The BCIE (Central American Bank for Economic Integration) serves as an ATM to supply cash for more publicly unpopular projects, chained to the IDB like a bulldog because of its more aggressive approach to lending.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>International Monetary Fund</label>
      <region x="0.00034" y="0.22474" width="0.09022" height="0.10883"/>
      <html>
        When a country&#x2019;s economy is in crisis, the IMF is called in to give bailout loans to use to
        pay the interest on existing debt. It implements Structural
        Adjustment Programs (SAPS) that tie harsh conditions to these new loans. In the operating
        room, the IMF is gutting public services and applying leeches as a reference to
        how it uses SAPS to suck the life out of the public sector
        and force them into even higher interest payments. Dam-defibrillators apply &#x201C;shock therapy&#x201D; to the economy
        and keep the patient (Mesoamerica) pinned to the surgeon&#x2019;s table. The syringe is symbolic of IMF conditions that open up the economy to extraction.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>WTO - The World Trade Organization</label>
       <region
        x="0.23726"
        y="0.00223"
        width="0.09302"
        height="0.08988"
      />
      <html>
        <p>The World Trade Organization serves as a judge of international trade disputes, favoring corporate interests at the expense of workers and the environment. The crumbling institution holds
        scales of injustice,
        protecting the interests of the 1% while
        leaving the people of
        the world to hang.</p>
        <p>A riot
        cop puppet tries to crack down on anti-globalization protesters in a game of whack-a-mole, but their diverse tactics allow them to continue popping up.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The World Bank</label>
      <region x="0.22957" y="0.22908" width="0.10287" height="0.10535"/>
      <html>        
        The World Bank, another
        important lending institution behind Project Mesoamerica, is portrayed as a
        potbellied gambler, addicted
        to the fossil fuel economy.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>The Clean
        Development Mechanism</label>
      <region x="0.18586" y="0.26669" width="0.07594" height="0.05890"/>
      <html>
        The World Bank is responsible in part for the Clean
        Development Mechanism
        (CDM), shown as a shady coin-operated chess game that the Bank plays with itself. The Clean Development Mechanism (CDM) allows dirty industry to get credits for building &#x2018;green&#x2019;
        projects in the global South. The credits are said to &#x201C;offset&#x201D; pollution without making industries cut back on polluting activities. Bulldozers and excavators push all the chess pieces out of their path, regardless of whether they&#x2019;re on the &#x201C;dirty&#x201D; or &#x201C;clean&#x201D; energy side of the
        game. 
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>The house always wins</label>
      <region
        x="0.24041"
        y="0.24819"
        width="0.07054"
        height="0.05800"
      />
      <html>
        The World Bank pours dollars into the carbon market by cutting out coins from a cloud of smoke while its other arm plays the slot machines, taking its chances with natural disasters. On the poker table in front of the Bank, the chips are stacked up against the global South. With loans tied to conditions like economic bear traps, the house always wins.        
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Greenwashing</label>
      <region x="0.12782" y="0.27144" width="0.07836" height="0.05607"/>
      <html>
        Major extractive
        industries sit at a
        boardroom table
        and cut up a cake in
        the shape of Mesoamerica, honoring
        500 years of colonialism. Trying to
        appear harmless in
        their animal disguises, these greenwashed industry representatives steal natural resources from Mesoamerica, as they hustle a small sampling of biodiversity onto Noah&#x2019;s Ark.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The biosphere reserve</label>
      <region
        x="0.07844"
        y="0.26800"
        width="0.05775"
        height="0.05095"
      />
      <html>
        <p>Under the guise of conservation, the biosphere reserve nearby appears as a guarded greenhouse - particularly referring to the Mesoamerican Biological Corridor, a project of the World Bank. This private-sector approach to conservation leads to evictions of Indigenous communities who have long been stewards of the land, while allowing industry to access &#x201C;protected&#x201D; areas for activities
        including oil prospecting. </p>
        <p>Eager for a photo op to
        try to improve their public image, the greenwashers hold up a false backdrop to attract visitors and investors from afar.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>El Campo Sin Campesino</label>
      <region
        x="0.00965"
        y="0.07446"
        width="0.04798"
        height="0.02504"
      />
      <html>
      <p>At the top of this cycle, a communally-farmed beehive is broken up
      into small hexagons.
      The Department of Agriculture and the Bank join forces
      to push for individual land titles and credit to
      finance this dismantling of collective and Indigenous lands.</p>
      <p>In 1992, anticipating the signing of NAFTA, the Mexican government changed its constitution to allow for the privatization of communal lands; a decade later, Central
      American countries faced the same privatization
      with the signing of CAFTA-DR.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Farmer Bee brings her corn to market</label>
      <region x="0.02902" y="0.08299" width="0.02734" height="0.03406"/>
      <html>
        <p>After a long and hard season working her little hexagon plot, Farmer Bee brings her corn to market, but her corn doesn&#x2019;t measure up.</p>

        <p>Free trade policies have opened the borders to dumping of cheaply produced corn from the
        United States, and Farmer Bee can&#x2019;t compete with prices set by an open market flooded with grain from subsidized, large-scale agriculture.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The bank comes to collect the interest on her land</label>
      <region x="0.00588" y="0.10393" width="0.04197" height="0.04371"/>
      <html>
        <p>When the bank comes to collect the interest on her land, she must break the bank, sell her
        land and join the many other economic refugees headed to the city to look for work.
        </p>
        <p>Farmer Bee takes one of the
        only jobs available, in a maquiladora (sweatshop), where she works in unsafe conditions for low wages.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The sewing machines in the maquiladora</label>
      <region
        x="0.00886"
        y="0.15383"
        width="0.03367"
        height="0.03048"
      />
      <html>
        The sewing machines in the maquiladora are sucking
        up traditional textiles and
        spitting out a line of mass-produced brand name clothing
        to flood the shopping malls of the global marketplace. 
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The mall</label>
      <region
        x="0.01020"
        y="0.16394"
        width="0.03437"
        height="0.04301"
      />
      <html>
        The mall has
        replaced
        the
        church as
        the new center of worship in town.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Looking deeper</label>
      <region
        x="0.01919"
        y="0.18977"
        width="0.03731"
        height="0.04363"
      />
      <html>
        Looking deeper, we see that the church was built directly on top of a Mayan pyramid, a literal reference to colonial history.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>Meanwhile, the de-populated rural areas&#x2026;</label>
      <region
        x="0.01068"
        y="0.08837"
        width="0.03209"
        height="0.03189"
      />
      <html>
        Meanwhile, the de-populated rural areas have been bought
        up for monocultures of
        cash crops and extractive
        energy projects.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Crossing the border to find work</label>
      <region x="0.03632" y="0.11654" width="0.02406" height="0.04276"/>
      <html>
        Through
        this cycle of
        displacement, some
        of the bees risk their lives crossing the border to find work. They disappear off to the north, maybe never to be heard from again.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The Quetzal bird</label>
      <region
        x="0.03574"
        y="0.21494"
        width="0.03426"
        height="0.03650"
      />
      <html>
        The Quetzal bird holds on to the social fabric of communities and steadily weaves cultural resistance, keeping alive textile traditions and the art of communicating through patterns and drawings.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Resistance and Repression</label>
      <region x="0.26958" y="0.07219" width="0.05830" height="0.07616"/>
      <html>
        <p>On the right side of the map,
        swarms of ants rise and fall
        in a cycle of resistance and repression. Troops force ants into
        a mass grave and firebomb their
        crops and villages, a direct reference to the scorched earth policy
        of the military dictatorship in Guatemala in the early 1980s, a genocide
        campaign that specifically targeted
        the Ixil Maya people.</p>
        <p>Guatemala&#x2019;s civil war is emblematic of the entire region&#x2019;s history, stemming from a long history of land grabs, inequality, racism, and U.S. intervention. Rising up from below, social movements continue to regroup and carry on struggles against militarization and for land reform, sovereignty, and justice, even when faced with the trauma of state brutality, mass arrests, and forced disappearances.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>A new form of violence against people
        and the land</label>
      <region x="0.25583" y="0.14025" width="0.07316" height="0.03453"/>
      <html>
        A tank-tractor merges the war machine with industrial agriculture, a new form of violence against people
        and the land. After World War
        II, factories that made tanks
        and explosives for war were put to new
        use and started pumping out tractors and fertilizers instead, leading
        to the world-wide Green Revolution and corporate control of agriculture. A mother stalk of corn is being assaulted and violated by the tank-tractor, sprayed with GMO seed and a toxic medley of chemicals.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>A Trojan horse rolls in&#x2026;</label>
      <region x="0.27423" y="0.16604" width="0.05589" height="0.04192"/>
      <html>
        A Trojan horse rolls in, sponsored by big agribusinesses who claim to be the solution to world hunger. An army of genetically-modified corn charges out, ready to attack.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>&#x201C;Corn&#x201D;quistadors</label>
          <region x="0.26673" y="0.17740" width="0.04294" height="0.05066"/>
      <html>
        <p>Like the Spanish conquistadors
        who used biological warfare,
        spreading disease to indigenous
        people of the Americas, these &#x201C;corn&#x201D;quistadors are destroying indigenous corn and food sovereignty with genetic contamination. One also wields
        a gas pump weapon as a reference to ethanol, an agrofuel from corn that is a false alternative to fossil fuels.</p>
        <p>Production of monocropped biofuels takes over huge swaths of land,
        depletes the soil, and contaminates water with fertilizers, while failing to address the consumption of fuel in the global North.</p>
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>The ants reemerge</label>
      <region x="0.29422" y="0.19671" width="0.03124" height="0.04385"/>
      <html>
        Below it all, the ants reemerge again as a symbol of popular resistance. While they are protesting at the top of the scene, here they are busy tending to the life cycle of corn that feeds and sustains their community: sowing and saving seeds, exchanging local varieties, and grinding corn into flour.
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>The Orb-weaver spider</label>
      <region x="0.25333" y="0.21704" width="0.04817" height="0.03624"/>
      <html>
        <p>The Orb-weaver spider, mirroring the efforts of the Quetzal bird on the opposite side, painstakingly works on weaving topsoil back together and healing the land.</p>
      </html>
    </story>


    <story>
      <label>The view from the grassroots</label>
      <region x="0.325" y="0.00000" width="0.675" height="0.33333"/>
      <html>
        <p>Opening up the poster, the world on the inside is drawn from the perspective of an ant on the ground at the base of a towering ceiba tree. This ground&#x2019;s eye view reflects the experiences of those who are rooted in a place and directly affected by the plans on the map. Between the roots of the ceiba, lively scenes illuminate stories of grassroots organizing and community resilience. This graphic documents many examples
      of alternatives to top-down development plans, highlighting resistance led by Indigenous peoples who have fought back against genocide and ongoing threats to their survival.</p>

        <p>The Ceiba tree&#x2019;s spreading buttress roots hold the scenes together and tell an overarching story of rootedness. This tree serves as a gathering
        place, a beacon in the center of town that brings people together to share stories and announce calls to action.</p>

        <p>A multitude of characters symbolize strategies and tactics
        for building and defending autonomy. Every critter in the poster is based on a real species native to somewhere between Mexico and Colombia. 400 individual species of insects, plants, and animals give a glimpse of the incredible biodiversity of the region.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
        <label>Two ghostly strands</label>
        <region x="0.3841966666666667" y="0.02315" width="0.09541379310344827" height="0.13564"/>
        <html>
          Two ghostly strands spiral down around the trunk of the ceiba. The creatures here are all extinct, endangered, threatened, or vulnerable, but in spirit they&#x2019;re alive and fighting fiercely. The strands are interwoven like the double helix of a DNA strand, to show the interconnectedness of the whole web of life.
        </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The upper layers of the canopy</label>
      <region
        x="0.75590"
        y="0.00592"
        width="0.10505"
        height="0.05420"
      />
      <html>
        The rainforest holds its richness in the upper layers of the canopy, which nurtures the life below. Once trees are cut down, the soil left behind is weak, and the ecological damage is irreparable. The loss of rainforests
        is mirrored by the loss of cultural heritage, which is also being rapidly fragmented and eroded.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The spinal cord of Plan Mesoamerica</label>
        <region x="0.9070966666666667" y="0.01299" width="0.03771034482758621" height="0.05512"/>
      <html>In the top right corner of
    the poster, power lines march over the horizon. Under construction since 2007, the electric interconnection plan (SIEPAC) lays the groundwork for powering factories and industrial infrastructure. Power lines that would ultimately stretch from
    Colombia to North America particularly threaten the communities and ecosystems of the Darien Gap, a large stretch
    of wetlands and forests along the border between Panama and Colombia where there are no roads (the only gap in the Panamerican Highway). While energy is generated to meet the demands of big business, some rural communities lack access to electricity for basic needs or face exorbitant rates. A mob of birds flies at the tower, knocking it down and re-wiring for energy on a local scale.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Hydroelectric Dams</label>
      <region
        x="0.86834"
        y="0.09277"
        width="0.04385"
        height="0.04293"
      />
      <html>One foot of the power tower sucks its energy from a hydroelectric dam, flooding out entire villages and putting vast areas
    of habitat underwater. The dam, dubbed Clean Development,
    is backed with military might
    and produces electricity to power far removed factories and transport routes.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>A wave of letters</label>
      <region
        x="0.84452"
        y="0.09691"
        width="0.04787"
        height="0.02746"
      />
      <html>A wave of letters from the public flies at the dam, as people take up their pens in defense of their community. The high
    volume of public opinion fractures the dam and opens up time and space for a variety of resistance tactics to be used.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Social Spiders</label>
      <region
        x="0.81812"
        y="0.08907"
        width="0.03913"
        height="0.02802"
      />
      <html>In the shadow of the power
    lines, social spiders stitch together an urban squat as they
    collaboratively rebuild their
    community. Economic forces
    have pushed them to the margins of
    the city, yet they continue working together. Social spiders are not territorial or aggressive like many solitary species, but instead cooperate to build massive nests to care for their entire community. In the face of large scale development projects that threaten to uproot their new homes, the spiders are a reminder of urban struggles for land rights and recognition.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>The Land Grab</label>
      <region
        x="0.91035"
        y="0.11395"
        width="0.07064"
        height="0.06927"
      />
      <html>A monolithic copy machine dominates the righthand side of the poster as it
    spews out one-size-fits-all development plans. This machine rips
    up land, forcing it through
    a paper tray into where gas pumps write with oil-barrel toner. The pre-written plans speed on to the second level
    where
    whirlygig
    businessmen shake
    hands, rubber stamp permits, and exchange stacks of cash. The top of the copier spits out blueprints for large-scale infrastructure development projects.
    </html>
    </story>

      <story>
        <label>Bulldozer</label>
        <region
          x="0.92785"
          y="0.20605"
          width="0.05096"
          height="0.03995"
        />
        <html>The road-paving bulldozer cuts
      through rural and urban areas
      alike in order to provide easy
      and quick getaway routes for
      trucks hauling their goods across
      borders. Over 80% of Project Mesoamerica&#x2019;s funding is going towards
      transportation infrastructure, but these are highways being built for big industry, not for communities. Superhighways that claim to &#x201C;connect Mesoamerica&#x201D; are actually making large areas of land impassable for pedestrians and migratory animals, displacing homes and productive farmland, and charging high tolls that limit public use.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Airport</label>
        <region
          x="0.86607"
          y="0.10895"
          width="0.07993"
          height="0.06722"
        />
        <html>A cornfield faces off against an airplane
    trying to land at a new airport outside of Mexico City, one of the first projects proposed as part of
    Plan Puebla Panama.
    People in the town of San Salvador Atenco organized and successfully fought back to keep their land from being expropriated for the
    airport. This image of campesinos in Atenco, wielding machetes to defend their land, quickly became
    emblematic of popular protest against the PPP.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Three fronts of resistance working together</label>
        <region
          x="0.90137"
          y="0.16739"
          width="0.07978"
          height="0.05755"
        />
        <html>
          <p>Farmers, teachers, and workers are joining forces to tackle the tentacles of the land grabbing copy machine. These important social sectors are represented by three of the most important crops in the region, culturally and nutritionally: the three sisters of corns, beans, and squash.</p>
          <p>Planted together in milpas, a traditional system of farming in Mesoam&#xE9;rica, these plants support each other, each improving the growth of the others.</p>
        </html>   
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Tequio</label>
        <region
          x="0.85575"
          y="0.20135"
          width="0.04154"
          height="0.02341"
        />
        <html>
        Little beansprouts are learning
    about the value of Tequio, or collective work, from their teachers who are on strike and still educating their students through the struggle. The concept
    of a community coming together and all pitching in to get work done is found in many cultures and languages throughout the world.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>The People's Media</label>
        <region
          x="0.83729"
          y="0.15636"
          width="0.07284"
          height="0.05128"
        />
        <html>
          <p>The pedal-powered media machine rides into the scene, using media by
          and for the people. They cut through the stream of development plans
          from the copier with their screen-printed posters, as
          they record stories from the frontlines and broadcast
          them through alternative, independent media. The bees are taking the power of the
          media into their own hands to build resistance movements, from small-scale distribution of pamphlets to bold takeovers of mass media, like in Oaxaca in 2006.</p>
          <p>The free media machine catapults seed bombs at the land grab. The seed balls are a mix of seeds, soil, and clay that serve to reclaim damaged land for cultivation.</p>
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Tourism</label>
        <region
          x="0.88317"
          y="0.24937"
          width="0.10519"
          height="0.07605"
        />
        <html>In the bottom right corner of the poster, a cruise ship invades the coast. The ship is based off an amphibious landing&#xFFFC;craft used by the U.S. marines to deploy troops on the shores of Central America. The chompy teeth are tourists going on holiday to unwind as they gobble up a packaged experience.
    They don&#x2019;t see beyond billboards that offer up Indigenous culture for sale and entertainment, and local people for serving food and cleaning toilets. Relying on racism, the tourist industry exploits local communities of color while selling the idea that a privileged
    few are entitled to their vacationland.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Behind the billboard facade</label>
        <region
          x="0.86299"
          y="0.22265"
          width="0.06844"
          height="0.05331"
        />
        <html>
          <p>A two-sided billboard works to homogenize all cultures and keep peoples thoughts only skin deep, as it sells tanning lotion to white tourists and skin whitening cream to local people of color.</p>
          <p>Behind the billboard
    facade, a real-life manatee, crab, and turtle are representatives of coastal communities fighting for recognition of ancestral lands. Defending their cultural
    identity, the Indigenous Garifuna communities on the Atlantic Coast
    are confronting paramilitary violence, which is used to enforce Illegal land sales. Their drums break through the colonial lie of &#x2018;discovering empty beaches.&#x2019;</p>
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Market</label>
        <region x="0.6915633333333333" y="0.22277" width="0.11317241379310344" height="0.07836"/>
        <html>
    Shopping carts pushed by
    genetically modified palm, corn,
    and soy creatures are rushing in
    on newly-paved highways, attempting to invade a traditional local market with an arsenal of junk food and
    copyrighted genetic bombs. The
    market resists the invasion with
    the strength of its cultural and ecological diversity, forming a blockade of DNA strands to keep out these mono-cropped monsters of industrial agriculture.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Meanwhile, an 18-wheeler truck&#x2026;</label>
        <region x="0.7879033333333334" y="0.24775" width="0.08536551724137931" height="0.07817"/>
        <html>
          Meanwhile, an 18-wheeler truck, hauling in mass produced, highly subsidized, and nutritionally void &#x201C;food products&#x201D;
    confronts another blockade on the right side of the market. This blockade is formed by youth who are also sending these big brands a message: take back your trash!
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Inside the market</label>
        <region x="0.6829766666666667" y="0.19723" width="0.13728275862068964" height="0.05088"/>
        <html>
          <p>Inside the market, local economies and native food systems thrive. All the vendors are pollinators, the creatures that flowering plants need to produce fruit. Providing habitat for pollinators is an essential part of healthy, biodiverse farming.</p>
          <p>The yucca moth, for example, is the sole pollinator of yucca; without this moth, the yucca plant can&#x2019;t go to seed.
          All the shoppers in the market are seed dispersers, and the market itself represents a living seed bank.</p>
          <p>Everywhere there is food in this scene, seeds are included: vendors are packaging, exchanging, collecting, and sprouting seeds, nurturing hundreds of local varieties of plants and protecting their food sovereignty for generations to come.</p>
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Women on the front lines</label>
        <region
          x="0.52261"
          y="0.23689"
          width="0.13150"
          height="0.09259"
        />
        <html>
          <p>A scheming puppet master stands at a podium, controlling the many forms of military force that carry out the list of conquests. The use of force against people has taken many forms throughout the Americas, including death squads, private security forces, militarized riot police, organized crime, and plain-clothed paramilitary.</p>
          <p>The invaders are unable to advance as they find themselves surrounded by a blockade of women
      defending their land, safety, and community. Each character carries a marking of a female and is using
      her natural defenses, like the porcupine who has shot her
      quills into the face of the paramilitary.
      Women and children put themselves on the front lines during countless standoffs between armed forces and unarmed civilians in defense of their communities.
          </p>
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Ancestors, &#xA1;Presente!</label>
        <region
          x="0.63641"
          y="0.22227"
          width="0.05696"
          height="0.06061"
        />
        <html>
        An ancient glyptodont roars and swings her armored tail, representing the spirits of ancestors that are being disturbed by the mine. Skeletons of extinct animals appear in a few other scenes, their presence reminding us of all who have come before us in the struggles for justice.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Open pit mine</label>
        <region
          x="0.64471"
          y="0.27981"
          width="0.06075"
          height="0.05041"
        />
        <html>
        Giant mining machines dig into the earth, employing dangerous and exploitative labor practices while disregarding the environment and health of nearby communities. Cerrejo&#x301;n, the worlds largest open pit coal mine,
        forcibly removed Wayuu and Afro-Colombian communities from their land. Cyanide leaching from Goldcorp&#x2019;s Marlin mine in Guatemala has severely contaminated the groundwater. Both have served as warnings and case studies for the organized resistance to mining across the Americas.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Water for Profit</label>
        <region
          x="0.35084"
          y="0.20376"
          width="0.08144"
          height="0.07313"
        />
        <html>
          <p>The monster of water privatization looms over the stream, seizing water
          from the commons and locking it away with dollar
          values. Giant drinking straws feed into a tower of industries that rob communities of their drinking water through over-use and pollution.
          Stacked from top to bottom are: bottled water, mining,
          textiles, cattle ranching, and golf courses. The water trucks on chain
          leashes are fierce attack dogs protecting the interests of the water monster; one truck sells
          drinking water, while the the other blasts water mixed with tear gas to disperse protests.
          </p>
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>A trio of water creatures</label>
        <region
          x="0.42620"
          y="0.18108"
          width="0.04465"
          height="0.05436"
        />
        <html>
          Taking a stance on the nearby tree root, a trio of water creatures are caught in a tug-of-war. Pulling with all their might, they work
    to take back the water for its use as a life giving force.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Water for life</label>
        <region
          x="0.39513"
          y="0.13663"
          width="0.07514"
          height="0.08856"
        />
        <html>
        Moss covered toad statues illustrate the age-old uses of water &#x2014; drinking,
        cooking, bathing, and washing. At the top of the stream an Uo toad signifies the rainy season
        and fertility brought by water. A reminder that water is life, the toads&#x2019; everyday use of water for basic needs is a form of resistance to selling off water to private interests.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Reclaiming water from pollution</label>
        <region
          x="0.39598"
          y="0.24645"
          width="0.04065"
          height="0.03875"
        />
        <html>Underfoot of the menacing water monster, a team of bacteria
    form a bucket-brigade to collect the polluted water and reclaim
    it through a &#x201C;living machine&#x201D;
    filtration system. Polls of living
    organisms from reeds, lilies, and
    water hyacinth to snails and clams work together in a multistage process of water purification.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Pirate Radio</label>
        <region
          x="0.34017"
          y="0.27574"
          width="0.06283"
          height="0.04133"
        />
        <html>
          The independent radio station or radio libre (free radio) beams out news and culturally valuable music over the airways. In situations where mass media is tightly controlled by oppressive governments, community radio may be the only way for transmitting critical information about social movements. Using a small-scale water wheel, the station powers itself as an example of autonomous energy production.
        </html>
      </story>


      <story>
        <label>Golden toads</label>
        <region
          x="0.40479"
          y="0.28906"
          width="0.04238"
          height="0.02811"
        />
        <html>
        <p>
        Frogs and toads are highly sensitive to changes in an ecosystem and serve as warning signs of environmental catastrophe. The demise of the golden toad marked the first time
    that the scientific establishment officially attributed an extinction to climate change, but they are not the only victims. Against all odds, a ring of eggs floats in the water around the mating toads, reminiscent of cycles of the moon.
        </p>
      </html>
      </story>


      <story>
        <label>Birth</label>
        <region
          x="0.43400"
          y="0.20008"
          width="0.07468"
          height="0.09208"
        />
        <html>
    Deep inside a womb-like cave formed by the tree roots, a scene of fertility portrays a
    vampire bat midwife assisting a birth. She is surrounded by herbal medicines used for traditional and Indigenous healing practices. The plants hanging in the cave are all related to fertility and women&#x2019;s reproductive health. Midwifery and other non-Western medical practices have resiliently survived despite the bio-medical industry&#x2019;s attempts to discredit and destroy them.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Coastal Monoculture</label>
        <region
          x="0.34954"
          y="0.16238"
          width="0.07142"
          height="0.05691"
        />
        <html>A bulldozer
    crashes through the roots of a mangrove ecosystem, dragging in fencing and
    an industrial shrimp farm in its wake. Mangroves protect the coast from erosion with their massive root systems, creating a unique ecosystem, nursey, and sanctuary for young aquatic creatures. Industrial shrimp farming is a rapidly growing industry that threatens mangroves worldwide. This polluting monoculture displaces the marine life which provides essential protein sources for local communities.
        </html>
      </story>
      

      <story>
        <label>Refugees</label>
        <region x="0.34861000000000003" y="0.10054" width="0.06023448275862069" height="0.06598"/>
        <html>Crying out in alarm, a flock of birds bursts into the air above the disturbed mangrove forest. The birds clutch their nests and young, forced to flee as their habitat is destroyed by infrastructure projects. The birds also tell a story of people who fled the scorched earth policies, genocide, and civil wars in Guatemala, El Salvador, and Nicaragua from the 1960s-1980s. The broken nests show the destruction and separation of families in exile.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Returning</label>
        <region
          x="0.47889"
          y="0.01787"
          width="0.07330"
          height="0.05788"
        />
        <html>
          <p>Emerging
        from the forest canopy, the
        birds return home after
        the war. Some of them had organized in exile and fought to
        return home as recognized organizations.</p>
        <p>Youth are recording historic memory by interviewing their elders and broadcasting to the whole community.</p>
        <p>They carry examples of organizing and solidarity: a childcare cooperative, saving seeds and planting hope for the future, weaving as a metaphor for the social fabric of
        community, mobilizing and educating through
        petitions and independent media. At the front of the line two young birds remind us that
        youth are leaders in the movement, carrying photos of the
        disappeared.</p>
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Fiesta</label>
        <region
          x="0.49189"
          y="0.14090"
          width="0.10913"
          height="0.11294"
        />
        <html>
          Spirits and the living mingle together in this lively
    fiesta, as they sing and dance in honor of
    the four elements surrounding the scene; earth, air, water,
    and fire. Gathered around the fire, elders and ancestors pass down wisdom to a
    younger generation &#x2014; sharing stories of resistance, knowing that wins, losses, and the
    journey between are all
    reasons to come together. When existence is resistance, the seemingly simple act of gathering carries great significance.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Historical memory</label>
        <region
          x="0.45659"
          y="0.25437"
          width="0.09303"
          height="0.05482"
        />
        <html>
          <p>In the roots below the bat cave and the
          fiesta, caterpillar youth are painting a mural
          of a monarch butterfly in a field of corn,
          the pattern on its wings morphing into
          strong fists of struggle. The butterfly has
          been widely used in today&#x2019;s migrant rights movements as a symbol of freedom and courage to cross borders.</p>
          <p>The caterpillars in this scene were inspired by meeting with HIJOS in Guatemala, a group formed a few years after the peace accords in 1996. They are the children of those who were disappeared during the civil war, still fighting for justice. Murals
          educate about the past and keep collective memory alive, using art as to transform a
          violent history into something filled with beauty
          and power. The youth are
          surrounded by references
          to memory and oral history.
          Flowers, plants, a conch shell, music, and traditional weavings are all passing knowledge and stories down through generations, their voices spiraling out in the form of volutas. The voluta is like a speech bubble. It is adapted from a Mayan glyph representing speaking and listening. Throughout the poster it symbolizes the power of the word.</p>
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>    
        <label>The community assembly</label>
        <region
          x="0.58781"
          y="0.11760"
          width="0.12971"
          height="0.11808"
        />
        <html>
          Representatives of communities affected by Project Mesoam&#xE9;rica gather in a circle at the center of the poster to discuss their common struggles and plans for collective action. Some of the
          characters bring items from their communities, signaling that they&#x2019;ve traveled far to be here, and that organizing efforts have been coordinated
          across the region. Unlike the top-down decision making that governs the &#x201C;official&#x201D; plans for the region, many voices are valued in
          his process of participatory, horizontal communication. The stories transmitted at this gathering join together in a spiral that
          symbolizes the conversation taking
          place. Documenting and spreading the word is also essential; recording equipment appears around the circle to foster communication between generations and across cultures.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>The Ant Swarm</label>
        <region
          x="0.42352"
          y="0.07800"
          width="0.14023"
          height="0.10712"
        />
        <html>
          <p>A giant swarm of ants comes down the trunk of the Ceiba tree. The ants, like so many other little critters, play an essential role in the ecosystem. Scurrying beneath the dirt, they aerate the soil, making it possible for plants to grow, essentially laying the foundations for life on earth. While these ants seem small in the face of the entire forest, they outweigh all other animals and plants combined. The ants remind us that great changes are in the hands of the small and many. Working tirelessly, these miniscule creatures embody the phrase,
          la revoluci&#xF3;n es el trabajo de las hormigas (the revolution
          is ant&#x2019;s work). Little by little, their collective work has the strength to achieve great transformations, which reminds us that together, we can create tremendous changes in the world around us.</p>

          <p>
            Some of the ants proudly
            carry messages from Indigenous communities in southern Mexico who have been slowly and steadily building autonomy for several decades. These sayings are Zapatista principles and also come from their experience of building &#x201C;good government&#x201D; councils, which encourage frequent rotation of leadership: &#x201C;lead by obeying&#x201D; the people in your community, they advise; &#x201C;work from below, without seeking to rise to power;&#x201D; &#x201C;walk by asking questions.&#x201D; Each ant is a different species, reminding us that the beauty of the world lies in its diversity - of cultures, of languages, of ways
            of being: &#x201C;we are the same because we are different;&#x201D; &#x201C;a world where many worlds fit.&#x201D; In the face of so
            many threats to the diversity of life on this planet, the ants converge at the base of the Ceiba to declare &#x201C;Ya basta! Enough!&#x201D;
          </p>
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Stories of Bees and Economies</label>
        <region
          x="0.69067"
          y="0.08385"
          width="0.17838"
          height="0.10441"
        />
        <html>
          <p>As European colonists invaded Central America, they brought with them the invasive European honey bee, which aggressively began to push the native Mesoamerican stingless bees out of their ecological niche. Today, deforestation, pollution, and industrial farming are destroying habitat and causing the collapse of pollinator species all over Central America. Bees are an indicator species, and the drastic decline of their populations may forecast a larger ecosystem collapse. Restoring native bee populations is vitally important to the health of ecosystems and agriculture globally, and is directly linked to the survival of Indigenous peoples and beekeeping knowledge. Traditional beekeeping is an intimate relationship between bees, people, culture,
          and the land.</p>
          <h4>Vanilla and stingless bees</h4>
          <p>Pollinators and the plants they
          pollinate need each other. The
          native Melipona bee and the vanilla plant share one of these specific symbiotic relationships. Melipona bees from southern Mexico are the only natural pollinators of the delicate vanilla orchid. Without this specialized interaction, vanilla orchids would only survive by hand pollination, making vanilla one of the most labor intensive crops in the world.</p>
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>An Alternative Economy: Design</label>
        <region
          x="0.80081"
          y="0.11300"
          width="0.03985"
          height="0.03419"
        />
        <html>
          Each terrace of the hive is buzzing as bees work on designing an economy to provide for their needs. As opposed to the accumulation of wealth that is central to the capitalist economy, this economy is centered around health, food, shelter and wellbeing. The Bees plan their economic system by studying the health and structure of their hive, taking notes, and mapping out routes for gathering local resources.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>An Alternative Economy: Production</label>
        <region
          x="0.83676"
          y="0.12625"
          width="0.03351"
          height="0.04637"
        />
        <html>
          Carpenter bees and other species of solitary bees
    show solidarity by building
    habitats for other pollinators. A worker-owned print shop produces paper from recycled materials.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>An Alternative Economy: Exchange</label>
        <region
          x="0.80657"
          y="0.17848"
          width="0.05124"
          height="0.04062"
        />
        <html>In contrast to the exploitative maps made by the colonizers, bumble bees, mason bees, and carder bees are mapping out a solidarity economy that is mutually beneficial. A bee on a conch shell phone busily takes orders while others prepare to send out bundles of heirloom seeds, honey, tortillas, candles, bee houses, and books, as part of a regional network that relies on local skills and goods.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>An Alternative Economy: Eating together</label>
        <region
          x="0.76350"
          y="0.15713"
          width="0.05982"
          height="0.04082"
        />
        <html>
          These bees have invited friends over for a meal and for a popular education workshop about direct trade. They explain how to connect with local farmers to get food straight
          from the farm to the table, cutting out the middleman. They use local bark to make DIY    biogas that heats the comal for cooking tortillas;
          next to it the same bark is
          mixed with honey to make
          balch&#xE9;, a traditional fermented mead.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>An Alternative Economy: Dividing the hive</label>
        <region
          x="0.80148"
          y="0.13415"
          width="0.04026"
          height="0.02567"
        />
        <html>
          Bees work on dividing the hive, a skill passed down through the generations by oral tradition. The stingless bees are kept in a specially-made box, as the bee logs (stacked on the left side of this scene) are in short supply due to deforestation. Survival of Melipona bees depends on knowledge from elder beekeepers. In conservation efforts, some scientists with &#x201C;zoo&#x201D; mentalities have destroyed hives they tried to protect by collecting them for study in labs. The stingless bees remind
          us of the vital connection between culture and ecology.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>An Alternative Economy: Reinvestment</label>
        <region
          x="0.77623"
          y="0.11647"
          width="0.03535"
          height="0.02750"
        />
        <html>
          <p>Unlike the one-way flows of the global economy, resources in the hive are recycled and reinvested.</p>
          <h4>Seed saving</h4>
          <p>Harvesting seeds and saving them to grow a new set of crops next season, the bees build sustainable sovereign food systems that will continue to feed their peoples
          for generations. Saving seed is an example of self-sufficiency and independence from industrial agriculture.
          </p>
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>An Alternative Economy: Composting</label>
        <region
          x="0.73793"
          y="0.15154"
          width="0.04601"
          height="0.02686"
        />
        <html>
          Turning food
          scraps and garden
          waste into lush
          fertile soil, the
          bees and worms
          build future food
          systems, literally starting from the ground up.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>An Alternative Economy: Most valued assets</label>
        <region
          x="0.69668"
          y="0.08957"
          width="0.06543"
          height="0.03289"
        />
        <html>
          <p>Safeguarded at the top of the hive, the bee larvae are highly valued as they provide the base of the next generation and an investment
          in the future. Seeds and eggs are the currency
          of the economy that runs this bee
          society; they are the
          concentrated units that all life comes from, and speak to the symbiotic relationship between plants and pollinators.</p>
          <h4>Seeds of the future</h4>
          <p>As the larvae grow, so does their education. The newbees
          learn to cooperate and play together while pumping out honey with a seesaw. Other youth share what they&#x2019;ve learned about the colonial invasion of European stinging bees, through a mural and
          a play. Kites soar above, celebrating the young bees&#x2019; irrepressible spirit of resistance.</p>
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>An Alternative Economy: Astronomers</label>
        <region
          x="0.71697"
          y="0.07646"
          width="0.02847"
          height="0.02040"
        />
        <html>
          At the top of the hive, Melipona bees study the cosmos, learning from the cycles of the earth and moon. Informed by these natural cycles, the community can plan for planting and cultivating.
        </html>
      </story>

      <story>
        <label>Globalization from below</label>
        <region
          x="0.47381"
          y="0.08510"
          width="0.41141"
          height="0.19320"
        />
        <html>
          <p>Facing the serious dangers of colony collapse, over 50 bee species have come together to build an alternative economic system that emphasizes horizontal and equitable relationships, while providing the basic needs of their community.</p>
          <p>The values of an extractive economy have led us to a mass extinction crisis and climate chaos. The holistic values of a solidarity economy are part of the antidote to this crisis. Like the bees, rebuilding local and regional networks can help us deal with the challenges and consequences of a rapidly changing planet. All the critters defending their land between the roots of the Ceiba are showing us the meaning of globalization from below: reaching out across borders, cultures, and generations to link movements and support each other&#x2019;s struggles for survival.
          </p>
        </html>
      </story>


  </stories>
</data>
