<?xml version="1.0"?>
<data>
  <title>
      My Idea of Freedom
  </title>
  <link>https://bigideasforbees.wordpress.com/2014/12/26/story-telling-like-a-super-organism-a-4-week-course-at-srishti-design-school/</link>
  <stories>  

    <story>
    <label>Introduction</label>
      <region x="0.00000" y="0.00000" width="1.0" height="0.8"/>
      <html>        
      <p>“I am Tibetan, but I am not from Tibet. Never been there yet I dream of dying there” – Tenzin Tsundue</p>

      <p>‘My Idea of Freedom’ is an art collaborative by students of Srishti School of Art, Design &amp; Technology with the US based organization <a href="http://beehivecolletive.org">The Beehive Collective</a>. Through this initiative we aim at giving a voice to the Tibetan stories that have been left unheard.</p>

      <p>Our interactions with a variety of Tibetan Migrants from all age groups gave us a glimpse of Tibetan history. By understanding the different nuances of the past and present, we have come up with an art piece which represents the plight of the present day Tibetan and their longing for a free homeland. Through these stories we got perspective into their  views regarding their forced migration and subsequent decades in exile which grew within them.</p>

      <p>Even after all these years of distress, it intrigued us as to why there haven’t been any violent protests. In order to understand the same, we had to delve into Buddhism. Using stories and motifs symbolic of the Tibetan culture, we have created this portable mural which will facilitate their nature of protest in a versatile manner. Through this journey we want to give the world a sense of the struggle, migration and adaptation Tibetans have lived with since time immemorial and continue to this day in the hope of a place to call home.</p>

      <h4>Color Palette Relevance</h4>
      <p>The five colors symbolize the five elements.</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Blue symbolizes sky and space.</li>
        <li>White symbolizes air and wind.</li>
        <li>Red symbolizes fire.</li>
        <li>Green symbolizes water.</li>
        <li>Yellow symbolizes earth.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>According to traditional Tibetan medicine, health and harmony are produced through the balance of these five elements.</p>
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Dalai Lama: Between the Walls.</label>
      <region
        x="0.09922"
        y="0.50771"
        width="0.14672"
        height="0.10489"
      />
      <html>
        “When I was a little girl I always wondered why there wasn’t a single picture of His Holiness The Dalai Lama in our home. Every time I asked my mother she told me that it was none of my business and brushed me off. Due to lack of space in Tibet, we generally build and rebuild our houses at frequent intervals. During one of these instances, I found a space between two adjacent walls and, in that space I found the edge of a photo-frame peeping out. I was curious to know what it was and on further breaking down the wall, I found what I had always suspected. It was a picture of His Holiness, The Dalai Lama, with the head monk and my ancestor. On acquiring this hidden possession, I had several questions to ask but they were left unanswered till I came to India and understood the magnitude of the Tibetan conflict. Now I realize why my mom always avoided that question, it wasn’t out of ignorance but she was just trying to protect me. As children, we tend to discuss issues publicly without realizing the repercussions.”
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>Of Migration, Adaptation, Occupation.</label>
      <region
        x="0.36338"
        y="0.26440"
        width="0.15227"
        height="0.17319"
      />
      <html>
        In 1959, after a continuous threat from the Chinese Government, His Holiness, The Dalai Lama fled to India and a vast majority of the Tibetan people followed him causing a mass exodus. Finding shelter in India, the native Tibetans had to look for jobs to sustain a living. They took up menial jobs in road construction and labour work. “I lost my father, a construction worker, when he was hit by a rock in his eye once at a mining site. After I was born, my mother fell sick and she used to rest in our refugee tent while the rest of them went to work. One day my uncle on seeing our condition decided to take me along with him to work as my mother was too weak to take care of me. That fateful day, a flood came and ravaged our entire refugee camp and took my mother along with it. I grew up in Tibetan orphan schools, being transferred from one city to another, leaving me with no place to call home. Eventually I got married and have been handling my own garments stall since the past thirty years. Though I could not complete my education, I worked hard enough to make sure my children don’t suffer the way I did and today, my daughter is a nurse in a reputed hospital in America and my son is taking off to Switzerland shortly!”
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>CITIZENSHIP</label>
      <region
        x="0.76333"
        y="0.20733"
        width="0.18239"
        height="0.20323"
      />
      <html>
        The Tibetans in India today, don’t have a permanent citizenship. They own a document called the RC (Registration Certificate) which they must renew every year in order to continue staying in India. They acquire their Tibetan passport from their own Government in exile and their Identity Certificate is given to them by the Indian Government. Due to the Tibetan conflict and their nationality, their passport only allows them to visit a limited number of countries. The issue of their identity is brought up many a times. In 2014 Lok Sabha elections, the Indian Government came up with ‘The Tibetan Rehabilitation Act’ which states that Tibetans born before 1987 are entitled to vote, and by doing so they will become permanent Indian citizens. However, only a small percentage of Tibetans came forward to vote. When Tenzin Tsundue was asked about why he didn’t vote, he explained that it would make all their efforts for a free Tibet redundant. An act passed in 2014 states that Tibetans now are entitled to equal citizenship rights in India without actually having to get an Indian citizenship.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>LOSAR</label>
      <region
        x="0.28645"
        y="0.43612"
        width="0.36075"
        height="0.34271"
      />
      <html>
        Losar is a Tibetan New Year festival which is celebrated during February-March every year. The festival dates are based on the Luna Calendar. During Losar, all the Tibetans come together to celebrate with their families. They traditionally light a bonfire on the 29th in which they give away their prayer offerings. They believe that on this day whatever you wish for wholeheartedly comes true. They prepare an assortment of dishes which are specific to the New Year celebration. They visit their holy monasteries and spend this time in a spiritual and generous atmosphere.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>FREE TIBET BANNER</label>
      <region
        x="0.62210"
        y="0.32554"
        width="0.17175"
        height="0.30350"
      />
      <html>
        In 2002, during the visit of The Chinese Prime Minister Xi Jinping to India, Tenzen Tsundue climbed the scaffolding of Hotel Oberoi and unfurled a ‘Free Tibet’ flag, in protest. He was arrested and subsequently jailed for a while. The police, finding no substantial proof against him set him free. After this declaration of their rebellion, Tsundue was acknowledged as a pioneer of a free Tibet. He however said that he was not alone and equal credit would go to all the Tibetans who went on a hunger-strike on the same day.
      </html>
    </story>

    <story>
      <label>COMMUNICATION</label>
      <region
        x="0.75758"
        y="0.36398"
        width="0.23449"
        height="0.37251"
      />
      <html>
        Initially when the Tibetan natives migrated to India, they couldn’t communicate with their families back at home. After talking to several Tibetans we realized that the situation isn’t as dire as before. Now, they are able to contact their families as per their own will, under certain restrictions. Calls from India to Tibet are tapped by the Chinese and any reference to the word Tibet can cause trouble.
      </html>
    </story>



  </stories>
</data>


